<nodes><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Maternity-Leave-A-Potential-Financial-Liability-To-Employers-/03-11-2017-130408</link><title>Maternity Leave: A Potential Financial Liability To Employers?</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>Employers need to bear the complete cost of compliance and providing childcare support to its employees, which was not addressed in the Maternity Benefit Act before</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Working women in India were welcomed with a maternity bill benefit of half a year, contrary to the long standing three months leave.The Lok Sabha had passed the historic mandate on 9th of March 2017, providing relief to approx. 2 million working women in the country.However, the private sector doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be favouring the bill, citing burden of 26 weeks of paid leave for an employee. It is extremely difficult for private sector to manage for an employee&amp;rsquo;s absence while paying for six months. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Giving another jolt to the private companies through a recent RTI reply, the government has confirmed that employers need to bear the complete cost of compliance and providing childcare support to its employees, which was not addressed in the Maternity Benefit Act before.Priya Krishnan, Founder &amp;amp; CEO, Founding Years Learning Solutions, India&amp;#39;s leading daycare company said, &amp;quot;A legislation that was seen as a boon for the women workforce and help bring more women back to work, is turning out to be a significant setback in women employability given the lack of strategic thought that seems to have gone into its roll-out. Through this RTI reply, the government has unfortunately confirmed the long-held fear of the corporates bearing the complete financial burden in complying with the Maternity Benefits Act.What this effectively does is that retaining women suddenly becomes a far more expensive proposition for employers. For women between 25-35 years in particular, this will be even more daunting as even before they can make significant progress in their careers, they are seen as a potential financial liability by prospective employers.She added, &amp;ldquo;While other countries provide voucher systems and subsidies, it is sad to see that in India, the government has diminished its own role in the larger objective except for mandating companies to implement this, that too mid-financial year.&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;Women employability and increasing its attractiveness cannot be only the employers&amp;#39; responsibility especially when the government has stated it as a legal goal.&amp;quot;</body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Nov 03 15:11:23 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/No-Jobs-In-India-Jobs-Growth-Not-In-Accordance-With-GDP-Growth/03-11-2017-130407</link><title>No Jobs In India: Jobs Growth Not In Accordance With GDP Growth</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>The number of employees have increased to 3.92 million in FY-17 from 3.85 million in FY-13, managing a growth of about 1%, while the GDP growth has been around 7%</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Employment is quite unstructured in India given the fact that a large part of the workforce is in the unorganized sector where it gets blurred.CERA Ratings agency have analysed the issue of job creation in the corporate sector for the last five years. The agency analysed 715 companies and found out the aggregate number of employees rising to 3.92 million in FY-17 from 3.85 million in FY-13. This is a CAGR (Compound Annual Growth Rate) of just about half a percent, which is quite low.This is much of an issue considering the consonance with GDP growth at the macro level, which grew by an increasing rate till FY16 before slowing down in FY17. This indicates that the organized corporate sector did not witness the growth in accordance with the GDP growth.Job data for last 5 years<a href=""><iframe src="//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/M9qGz/1/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" width="100%" height="305"></iframe></a><br><strong style="background-color: initial;">Cost of employment</strong>With regard to employment, the cost of employment to be borne by the companies also matters as it is a part of the committed expenditure and affects the overall profitability of the companies.CARE Ratings assessed the average salary bands across the sample companies. The salary bill and average salaries of the sample of 1,473 companies, suggests that aggregate salary bill has increased from FY15 to FY17, though salary pay out grew at a slower pace in FY17 at 8.36 percent than that in the previous year at 11.85 percent.Growth in employment is also associated with increased salaries over the years. The average salary per employee has increased consistently from Rs. 7.13 lakh in FY15 to Rs. 8.35 lakh in FY17.&amp;nbsp;<a href=""><iframe src="//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/kYUmh/1/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" width="100%" height="305"></iframe></a><br></body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Nov 03 15:08:19 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Banking-Sector-Gave-Maximum-Employment-In-FY17/03-11-2017-130406</link><title>Banking Sector Gave Maximum Employment In FY17</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Sectoral division of employment suggests that banks were seen to employ highest number of employees in FY17, roughly around 21 percent</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Where are the jobs? What happened to Modi&amp;rsquo;s promise of 1 crore jobs annually. It has been a tough year for jobs creation and some 1.5 million jobs were lost during January-April 2017, according to the Centre for Monitoring Indian Economy.Sectoral division of employment suggests that banks were seen to employ highest number of employees in FY17, roughly around 21 percent. Top 5 sectors with highest number of employment are banks, IT, mining, healthcare and textiles, collectively accounting for nearly 60 percent of the total employment.Eleven sectors having more than 1 lakh employees account for nearly 80 percent of the total employment. Out of 31 sectors, 13 sectors registered increase in employment in terms of growth such as retailing (47.89 percent), healthcare (12.46 percent), plastic products (8.30 percent), IT (6.66 percent) and electrical (5.74 percent) in FY16 while in FY17.As many as 16 sectors recorded positive growth in the employment, the highest being in electrical (14.85 percent), finance (11.24 percent) and trading (6.53 percent). &amp;nbsp;10 sectors witnessed growth in employment in both the years FY16 and FY17 such as retail, textile, healthcare, banks, electricals, IT, logistics, plastic products, chemicals and non-ferrous metal products.Best growing sectors<a href=""><iframe src="//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/Z4rgU/1/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" width="100%" height="351"></iframe></a><br><span style="background-color: initial;">Contrary to that, 12 sectors recorded negative growth in employment in FY16 as well as in FY17. FMCG, media &amp;amp; entertainment and paper exhibited fall in employment in FY17 after increasing in FY16. &amp;nbsp;On the other hand, crude oil, infrastructure, trading, automobile &amp;amp; ancillaries, finance and hospitality, which had recorded negative growth in employment in FY16, witnessed growth in FY17.</span>The employment growth in FY16, is dragged down by decline in employment in automobile and ancillaries, mining, power and finance while in FY17, the negative employment growth has emanated from reduction in employment especially in the mining, telecom and power sector.Worst growing sectors<a href=""><iframe src="//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/rblOf/1/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" width="100%" height="324"></iframe></a><br></body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Nov 03 14:59:56 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Women-In-Workplace-Will-Take-217-Years-To-Close-Down-On-Gender-Diversity/03-11-2017-130404</link><title>Women In Workplace Will Take 217 Years To Close Down On Gender Diversity</title><categories><category>Employee</category></categories><description>Gender diversity in the workplace is still quite significant across the world. With the current rate of change, women in the jobs will take 217 years to be at par with men</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Gender diversity in the workplace has been a much debatable issue for the welfare of the women and countries have started making progress in terms of gender diversity understanding that talent is a critical factor for growth and a further progress is expected.According to the LinkedIn &amp;ndash; WEF (World Economic Forum) Gender Gap report, the gender gaps at the industry level highlights that even though qualified women are coming out of the education system, many industries are failing to hire, retain and promote them. The report titled &amp;lsquo;Global Gender Gap Report&amp;rsquo; was compiled online in 144 countries, including India covering 12 industries.Given the current rate of change, the Global Gender Gap Report estimates it will take 217 years to close the economic gender gap.The average hiring of women has increased by 6 per cent across 12 industries in India. Further, sectors like energy and mining, manufacturing and real estate have seen the highest change in the percentage of the female hiring rate in the last 10 years. Surprisingly, education industry which initially had the third highest percentage of women hired showed slow growth over the years and dropped in the rank to become the sixth highest.Software and IT services, manufacturing and healthcare industries have shown the highest increase globally, while the energy and mining sector ranked among the lowest. Industries that have witnessed a high change in hiring of women have also seen an increase in their talent pool. Non-profit and education industries have peaked in their women talent pools and other industries continue to grow.The report analysed large gaps in the availability of women talent for entry-level positions and the demand for hiring in industries like manufacturing, energy and mining.As per the report, demand for women hires surpassed the supply in non-profit, media and communications industries. While women worldwide are making progress closing gaps in critical areas such as health and education, gender gaps in the workforce and in politics are quite large.</body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Nov 03 14:51:16 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Anxiety-Toll-Management-ATM-for-Workplace-Happiness/30-10-2017-129848</link><title>Anxiety Toll Management &#8211; ATM for Workplace Happiness</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>In our work life, productivity suffers as our unhappiness leads to lowered concentration, inadequate team work, and poor interpersonal relations. It also impacts the overall environment and culture. </description><author>Naveen Khajanchi</author><body>Happiness and Unhappiness are like Light and Darkness which keep coming and going - neither of them can be permanent. Yet most of us focus our attention on unhappiness. Emotions of anxiety, fear, need for approval, expectation from others, fill our time. We have the power to awaken the light of happiness within us. The realization of this power will drive the rest of the negativities away. Acceptance the 1st key of ATM for Happiness is very critical in dealing with stress . Carnegie Mellon University&amp;ndash;led study found that one component of mindfulness interventions is particularly important for impacting stress biology. Acceptance, or learning how to be open and accepting of the way things are in each moment, is critical for the training&amp;rsquo;s stress reduction effects.&amp;nbsp;We know that most of our adult lives are spent in the workplace. It is a major part of our lives, a source of livelihood and also happiness, elation or anger and frustration. So how can we awaken, live and experience more moments of happiness at the workplace? Let&amp;rsquo;s look through common workplace situations.1. Meeting a deadline: Most of us must have faced this common issue. There is an important deadline to submit a project at the work place. Consequently, you are late in reaching home. Perhaps, your family members have been waiting for you. There is anxiety about meeting the deadline and about not upsetting your family members. Both these activities are equally important. When the lines between your professional and personal lives start getting blurred, both your career and your family start suffering. The office work will always be at the back of your mind when you are with family and vice versa. You are not able to perform well in both of these spheres of your life. What do you do? Prioritization is one way to go about solving this problem. If you are prioritizing the deadline at office, then make sure that you keep people at home posted about being delayed and make alternate arrangements for their dinner. In office, you should focus on the task and take help if required to finish in time. Remember to balance out your priorities. Applying the ATM (explained towards the end of this article) framework will help in balancing the emotional need and objectivity of work.2. Fear of failure: Say you have to lead an important sales call. When the company has entrusted this important task to you, it also expects you to get only positive results. The pressure of performing brings about anxiety. The key here is preparation. Chalk out various options. Start looking at them from the client&amp;rsquo;s perspective. Put yourself in the client&amp;rsquo;s shoes and think about their preferences and way of thinking. Prepare yourself for the eventualities. Picture yourself emerging out of the negotiation with a win-win decision. It will help to drive that anxiety away. Anxiety Toll Management led me to the ATM for Happiness.3. Expectations: You are expecting to go home a little early on a Friday so that you get to spend time with your family. They have been neglected because of the long hours of work you have been putting in. You feel that your boss will allow you to go home early. But instead, he has planned a client meeting at the club. He expects you to join him. You have only two choices here- go for the client meeting with your boss, or refuse to do so and fall out of favor. All the hard work you have been doing will go up in a smoke. So you do what seems logical to you and go to the club with your boss for the meeting. If you accept the choice you made to attend the meeting and are happy about it, your performance with the client and the boss will be much better off. You can make it up to your family later. Your boss may even support you when you need time off. This is called expectation management. On the contrary if you stay back grudgingly and grumpily, no one is going to be happy about it. Your boss and client will notice this negative attitude. You family is anyway unhappy. Just your negative attitude makes it a situation where everybody involved is negatively affected. When you make a choice, go through with it whole-heartedly. The positivity that you bring out will make situations better. Acceptance is key to expectation management in the ATM framework.4. Approval from others: You put in hours of work into that power point presentation. You had all the data, the graphs and every possibility covered. And yet, the reactions you got were desultory. Nobody gave that approving nod that you thought you deserved. They just moved on to the next person without commenting on your presentation at all. When somebody asks you how the presentation went, you are in a negative frame of mind and reply curtly. In these times, you have to remember that it&amp;rsquo;s alright. The golden rule is, &amp;ldquo;No feedback is good feedback&amp;rdquo;. Shrug it off and continue to do your best. You will get your due eventually. Negativity gallops at a much faster pace than positivity. It is up to us to stop it and rekindle the belief in our positivity. Over analysis leads to paralysis of our minds. Self-acceptance and being tolerant to our non-perfect state helps.In our work life, productivity suffers as our unhappiness leads to lowered concentration, inadequate team work, and poor interpersonal relations. It also impacts the overall environment and culture. The workplace and the employee need to work towards making the environment more positive and engaging. The endeavor is to create a holistic, positive environment wherein most people feel safe and are yet able to work effectively so that they have superior performance over time and are in better health.What can the workplace do?1. Employee Engagement is the past, it&amp;rsquo;s now about happiness and social connection:Employees tend to go to work bored and unengaged and return home drained of all their energy. It&amp;rsquo;s a vicious cycle. Workplaces can ensure active employee engagement. A Happiness and Productivity studyi, says that increasing employee happiness make them more than 7%-12% more productive.Nicole Lipkin summarized people&amp;rsquo;s needs using the SLAM model: Social connection, Leadership excellence, Aligned culture, and Meaningful lifeii. &amp;ldquo;No matter how old you are, or your status, these are the things we need as humans. We underestimate the social connections &amp;mdash; they can make a mediocre job enjoyable. It requires leaders to pay attention to the pulse of the culture. We are so busy rewarding for performance that we forget to reward for the behaviors that make an organization a great place to work.&amp;rdquo; Lipkin also noted that the expectations millennials have for flexibility, investment in their development, and work&amp;ndash;life integration actually play more into our psychological need for autonomy, competence, and how we naturally interact with people than the industrial-age structures.Personally, I feel that people feel engaged and energized when they know the larger purpose of the organization, it&amp;rsquo;s long term strategy and are able to align it to their own inner purpose. The connect goes a long way in establishing workplace satisfaction.2. Evolving leadership and the atmosphere within the organizationMost people leave a company with some grievance against the leadership or the way things operate. The HR needs to be aware and take affirmative, positive actions, if the same pattern of grievance continues. In his article &amp;ldquo;The Psychopath in the C-Suite&amp;rdquo;iii, Manfred Kets de Vries, says that narcissism in leaders is on the rise and the SOB (Seductive Operational Bully) exists at all levels. When such a leader is identified, corrective action should be taken immediately. To ensure accountability, try introducing key performance indicators clearly tied to outcomes. Psychopaths typically don&amp;rsquo;t like to be called to account. A check on such leaders at an early stage can help channelize their energy in the right direction.At times they also ensure a gang up against people not toeing the line &amp;amp; that can be dangerous for the people &amp;amp; the work place atmosphere. Take charge &amp;amp; start creating a small group which can stand together when the need arises.3. Encourage Positive Emotions:University of Pennsylvania professor Martin Seligman has studied &amp;ldquo;positive psychology&amp;rdquo; extensively. His complex definition of &amp;ldquo;Happiness&amp;rdquo; includes experiences of positive emotions, combined with deeper feelings of engagement and meaning. He says that people see their work in three possible ways &amp;ndash;a. They see work as being a &amp;ldquo;job,&amp;rdquo; or a chore, and use the pay check as its rewardb. They approach work as a &amp;ldquo;career&amp;rdquo; and work to advance and succeedc. They see their work as a &amp;ldquo;calling&amp;rdquo; and find work fulfilling because it gives them feelings of meaning and purpose.Hire people with a heart, those who will happily do their work. It is also important to actively encourage social interactions by creating safe and judgment free spaces. Positive emotions will flow across and be reinforced at work.What can the employee do?1. Be grateful for what you have:People have three times more positive experiences than negative.iv And yet, we tend to focus only on the negative ones. Look out for and notice the good things in life. Remember them and feel grateful for them. Gratitude is the perfect antidote for better health and well being. Most people aspire for the CEO title not knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea to lead a team and be responsible for their performance. At times being able to do a role that we enjoy, learning from it and performing well is good enough.2. Focus on building relationships:By actively building positive relationships of mutual respect, you are more motivated to go to work and be around these people. Think of it this way- when we greet each other, it&amp;rsquo;s with a warm handshake of right hands. Yet to walk along we need to hold one right and one left hand. We build relationships because of our similarities. We continue and prosper in these relationships, because of the acceptance of each other&amp;rsquo;s uniqueness.3. Remember and practice the ATM of happiness:You can take charge of situations by accepting what you can control and what you cannot. Write down your options and look at them objectively. At times, it&amp;rsquo;s our fear of the unknown or our vulnerability that leads to negative emotions and thoughts. In retrospect, they may not seem so bad. If we learn to take charge of our thoughts, it will lead to all round positivity and happiness in our lives.Don&amp;rsquo;t play the blame game .The ATM of Happiness will help you-A - Accept the present situation with objectivity, let go of the past and stop worrying about futureT - Take charge of your thoughts, expectations, fears and hopes in a manner that negativity can be reset to positivityM - Make the best of what you have in an effective manner with gratitudeAs individuals, we are our own masters and must do our bit to be happy and spread happiness over unhappiness by being happy &amp;amp; doing an extra bit for others to be happy . ATM for Happiness is just the starting point of this journey wherein I welcome you to professionally connect with me &amp;amp; others who can be of help &amp;hellip;as many employees and Half of the CEO&amp;rsquo;s reported feeling lonely in their roles.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Oct 30 10:57:57 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Leaders-In-Future-Will-Have-To-Balance-Human-Workforce-And-Machines/26-10-2017-129603</link><title>Leaders In Future Will Have To Balance Human Workforce And Machines</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>In the future workplace in India, CEOs will have to focus on differentiating human capabilities and striking the right balance between humans and machines

</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Artificial intelligence and machine learning have started shaping the future of work in India, and leadership roles have to evolve with the top brass are expected to be watchful about long-term perspective rather than short-term pressures, says a PwC report.According to the report titled &amp;#39;Reimagining leadership: Steering India&amp;#39;s workforce in 2030&amp;#39;, future workplace will be characterised by competing and conflicting priorities and demands of its key constituents - organisation, employee, CEO and HR.While emotional and cognitive intelligence have proved to be critical to leadership success in the past, in the future workplace, &amp;#39;learning intelligence&amp;#39; will be the new leadership edge, the report said.Chaitali Mukherjee PwC India People and Organisation Partner said, &amp;quot;Traditional models of development are no longer sufficient to help leaders act fast and effectively in unpredictable circumstances; organisations will need to reimagine the talent development experience at the top of the pyramid in much the same ways as they do in the customer experience.&amp;quot;In the future workplace in India, CEOs will have to focus on differentiating human capabilities and striking the right balance between humans and machines. HR will become the guardian of the brand, focusing on creating the right culture and protecting the organisation against sustainability and reputational risks.Blair Sheppard, Global Leader - Strategy and Leadership Development, PwC said, &amp;quot;It is the responsibility of the leader to look into the future when making decisions, to ensure they are solving the immediate problems, while also preparing their organisation for the future.&amp;quot;</body><post-date>Thu, 2017 Oct 26 13:25:59 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Look-At-Employees-As-Humans-And-Invest-In-Their-Needs-VP-HR-GHCL/26-10-2017-129593</link><title>Look At Employees As Humans And Invest In Their Needs: VP HR, GHCL</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>GHCL has been recognized as a &#8216;Great Place to Work- Certified Company&#8217; by the Great Place to Work Institute.What makes it a great company? Rajesh Tripathi, VP &amp; Head-HR, GHCL shares his thoughts about the strategy behind it and more</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body><strong>GHCL has been recognized as a &amp;lsquo;Great Place to Work- Certified Company&amp;rsquo; by the Great Place to Work Institute. What has been the strategy?</strong>GHCL is creating a niche place for itself in the market; and can be witnessed by the accolades in the recent past which stands at its epitome. &amp;ldquo;The Great Place to Work&amp;rdquo; certification added an unprecedented and phenomenal accreditation to our work environment.As a company, we ponder about traits which keep our employees happy which would be a complex mix of vision, values, culture and strategy. By putting core values at the forefront we shifted our focus from looking at employees not as resource but as a human first and invest more on spiritual, psychological, emotional and physical fundamental needs. This makes employees self-sufficient to bring in the best of them to work every day. Our prime focus remains on continual improvement of trust, respect, compensation, camaraderie, internal communication, training, and diversity.<strong>What can be done to bring parity in employee appreciation and make them feel comfortable in the workplace?</strong>Our belief system promotes &amp;quot;Let the Ideas Trump Seniority&amp;quot;. The office culture is designed in a way that individuals feels that the organization cares about them and wants them to thrive, be it a meeting room or lunch time gathering at the canteen premises. This sentiment of parity is felt across the board and communicates loud about the transparency as desired by employees. Organization has required policies in place for employee appreciation which ranges from on the spot awards to exemplary awards irrespective of hierarchy.<strong>What are you hiring intentions? What are the areas you looking to hire from?</strong>It is only through continuous innovations in our products, technologies and services that we can keep up with the momentum of growth &amp;amp; success. Hence, we have taken a giant leap towards building a great team through &amp;ldquo;Right people at Right Place&amp;rdquo;. We are continuously hiring people and strengthening our talent bandwidth. As GHCL operates in heavy chemicals, textiles and consumer durables sector our major focus would be to tap best of the best talent in these domains. The hiring process will be online in the coming months.<strong>Job market across different sectors and places is looking low? When do you see it improving?</strong>As per Monster Employment Index 2017 report, manufacturing &amp;nbsp;sector (down 23%) has recorded the steepest year-on-year decline in 2017.Taking an in-depth insights into employment conditions, skills in demand, sector trends and salary benchmarks for set industries the sluggishness towards recruitment can be perceived taking in account the ongoing global slowdown compounded by talent scarcity for niche skills &amp;amp; competencies. This reiterates the need for upskilling amongst talent pool to remain relevant and agile amidst changing business landscape. Let&amp;#39;s be hopeful as the plunge seems to be temporary and should soon revive.<strong>Are there any disruptive HR policies that you have recently adopted? What has been done for employee welfare?</strong>Culture is by far the biggest sustainable advantage an organization can have in a business today, because it is near to impossible to replicate or imitate. GHCL feels that the policies that we have in place are very employee friendly and provides an environment for employees to thrive &amp;amp; flourish. We have re-engineered our approach towards policy making. We bring in quick policy changes whenever we see a need and scope for it. GHCL has very effective and robust policies including health insurance, accidental death, leave, higher education, advance loan system, car lease, club memberships, flexi working hours, training of your choice and financial planning education.<strong>How do you keep employees engaged, and keep employee morale high when the hiring is low?</strong>It is significant to keep our employees mind de-cluttered and free from distractions. We hold leaders &amp;amp; managers responsible as well as accountable for treating our employees with utmost respect and care at all times. We also encourage them to regularly recognize significant contributions employees make.We make sure our talents are geared well to take up the opportunities coming their way through on-the-job training programs and taking up cross functional projects and reinforce them with proper mentoring and coaching. We have created an environment that encourages our employees to focus on their most important priorities without interruption, including long-term projects and more strategic and creative thinking. We believe it&amp;rsquo;s worth an organisations time to make this kind of investment in our people.</body><post-date>Thu, 2017 Oct 26 13:01:01 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/-Keep-It-Simple-And-Natural-For-Great-Work-Platforms-/26-10-2017-129590</link><title>'Keep It Simple And Natural For Great Work Platforms'</title><categories><category>Employee</category></categories><description>Taking care of good employees is important to prevent them from lobbying. Niel Nickolaisen, Senior Vice President &amp; Chief Technology Officer and Steve Fairbanks, Vice President - Software Product, O. C. Tanner believe better communication between employees can yield better results</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Taking care of good employees is important to prevent them from lobbying. Niel Nickolaisen, Senior Vice President &amp;amp; Chief Technology Officer and Steve Fairbanks, Vice President - Software Product, O. C. Tanner believe better communication between employees can yield better results.<strong>How important is timely and frequent recognition for employees, and its importance to businesses?</strong>We do a significant amount of independent research into employee recognition and its impact on employee engagement and retention. We conducted a research asking employees &amp;ldquo;What motivates you to do your best work?&amp;rdquo; The answers ranged from &amp;ldquo;Promote me&amp;rdquo; for 4% of the employees to &amp;ldquo;Pay me more&amp;rdquo; for 7% to &amp;ldquo;Give me autonomy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Inspire me&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; both at 12% to &amp;ldquo;Recognize me&amp;rdquo; for 37%. What is the impact when the company or our manager formally recognizes the work we are doing? How much more engaged with and committed when the organization appreciates our effort and results?Thus, timely and frequent recognition results in lower employee turnover and improved outcomes. The data shows that those with the most effective recognition programs have lower turnover than their industry peers.<strong>What are some of the employee engagement trends across the world?</strong>The most important trends are that, in general, employee engagement is low (according to the Gallup Employee Engagement Survey around 33% in the United States and around 13% worldwide) and has not increased or decreased much over the past years. The research also shows that organizations with high employee engagement achieve much better results in the marketplace than those with average engagement. One more important trend is that as the connection between employee engagement and results becomes clear, human resource professionals and organizational leaders are making engagement and culture higher priorities.<strong>What are the secrets to a workplace culture to attract and retain employees?</strong>We believe that there are several factors that create a culture that attracts and retains employees. We call these factors the &amp;ldquo;Talent Magnets.&amp;rdquo;They include:Purpose &amp;ndash; People are attracted to organizations that have a compelling reason or purpose to their work. This goes beyond Mission or Vision or Values. This purpose is the value that the organization&amp;rsquo;s products and services deliver to the marketplace.Opportunity &amp;ndash; People stay with organizations that give them the opportunities to develop and improve their skills and pursue a career. This includes training and development as well as the opportunity to participate in projects and on teams that expand their capabilities.Success &amp;ndash; People like to be on a team that wins in the marketplace.Recognition &amp;ndash; As I described above, recognition and appreciation are critical drivers of retention. Timely, meaningful recognition cements the relationship between the person and the organization.Wellbeing &amp;ndash; Employees stay with organizations that care about their whole person. This means emotional, social and physical wellbeing.Leadership &amp;ndash; You might have heard the phrase: People don&amp;rsquo;t quit their organization, they quit their manager. Thus, improving the leadership abilities of managers in critical in attracting and retaining employees. If an employee trusts their leader, enjoys their relationship with their leader and their leader creates a positive culture, great work and outcomes result.<strong>What can be done to bring parity in employee appreciation and make them feel comfortable in the workplace?</strong>Organizations willing to settle for a world class program and culture, they can make employee recognition a priority. They can train leaders and managers to provide meaningful and sincere feedback and appreciation designed to improve the relationship between the manager and employee. They can be clear as to their purpose and use that purpose to inspire employees and help them connect their work to the purpose. They can encourage and support employees as they improve their skills and work on critical projects. And that can care, deeply, about the well being of the employees.<strong>What are the expansion plans of O.C Tanner in India and what has been the absolute growth in the last few years?</strong>We opened our sales and client support office in Mumbai about three years ago and operate a number of Indian companies as clients. Our engineers in Hyderabad do customise our software products for our larger clients and manage Android mobile app development.We will continue to add employees at our Hyderabad office and give them additional software engineering tasks and projects. Over the next 12-18 months, we will approximately double the number of employees in Hyderabad.<strong>How will innovation help in evolving great work platforms?&amp;nbsp;</strong>Our product innovations will come in several ways: Make it easier, simpler and more natural to recognize great work and outcomes, Develop compelling products that align with our Talent Magnets, and, by using leading edge technologies (machine learning, block chain, micro-services, et cetera) to deliver higher impact to our clients.</body><post-date>Thu, 2017 Oct 26 12:56:40 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/-Leaders-Develop-Slowly-In-A-Series-Of-Stages-/17-10-2017-128875</link><title>'Leaders Develop Slowly In A Series Of Stages'</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>Randy Slechta, President &amp; CEO, Leadership Management International (LMI) shares his thoughts about leadership being a key area of employee engagement, and the stages of development of a leader</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body><strong>How do higher engagement scores impact businesses?</strong>Studies have consistently shown significantly higher productivity, employee retention, employee wellness, higher revenues, and higher profitability for organizations with higher engagement scores. Engagement is essentially another term for motivation, in other words how much discretionary effort does an employee put into their job. This extra discretionary effort really makes the difference in organizational results.<strong>Why is leadership a key ingredient in driving higher levels of employee engagement?</strong>Engagement is predominantly created and driven by an employee&amp;rsquo;s immediate leader. It is this relationship that is the number one factor in engagement levels. An employee&amp;rsquo;s manager creates the bulk of an employee&amp;rsquo;s experience with the organization. The big question is what kind of leadership does an employee&amp;rsquo;s boss or supervisor utilize? So it is critical that effective leadership practices are implemented through the entire organization, not just at the executive level.<strong>What do leaders in the digital age do to transform their culture?</strong>The digital age has actually created more challenges for organizations. Unfortunately, culture is something that cannot be changed or transformed. Culture is the result of the many face-to-face interactions between employees of an organization. This is where real attitudes, mind-sets, beliefs and values are formed. Before the digital age, leaders and managers spent considerably more time in these interactions and thus were able to have more impact on their culture. With the advent of digital communication, leaders now spend considerably less time physically interacting with their teams. Consequently, culture has become much more difficult to change in this environment. It is imperative for leaders to spend more time with their teams if they ever hope to impact their culture.<strong>What are the leadership development programs in India and expansion plans?</strong>We have spent the last 50 plus years working with over 2 million leaders in 80 different countries, so we have learned a great deal about what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t in developing effective leaders. The real key is that leaders are developed through a long-term process, not through short, isolated events or interventions.We have discovered that leaders actually develop in a series of stages or steps. There are four primary stages of leader development.First is learning to manage themselves and manage their time and priorities. We call this personal productivity.Second is learning to lead themselves. This means developing a personal mission, clarifying their values, creating a productive work-life balance, and building a trustworthy character. We call this personal leadership.Third is the ability to lead, engage, empower, coach and motivate others. We call this motivational leadership.And fourth is being able to lead an entire organization to success. We call this strategic leadership.It is like maturing as a person, you can&amp;rsquo;t skip a step. What we have done is develop specific leadership development programs around these stages so that we can enable leaders to master and progress though the four stages. In India, we have been focusing on the first few stages and are just now rolling out the programs for the higher stages.<strong>What is the leadership scenario in India, how can leaders be trained for the challenges to lead?</strong>India&amp;rsquo;s greatest resource is its people. The entire key to India&amp;rsquo;s future success is its ability to access, mobilize and develop this incredible resource. Of course the only way to do that is through effective leadership.India&amp;rsquo;s challenge is that it has a long history of hierarchy, bureaucracy, and management. The goal is not to manage people, but rather to lead them. You can&amp;rsquo;t manage people to higher engagement or motivation; you can only lead them there. So India must overcome some long held beliefs and mind-sets about the leadership-management paradigm. You can&amp;rsquo;t change mind-sets though a memo, or a speech, or a book, or a policy. This will only happen through a process specifically designed to change these mind-sets. All of our development programs have been designed and built on a methodology of changing attitudes to enable real culture change and leadership development.<strong>One out of four leaders hired across the world is a woman, but they have a lesser working period. What can be done to promote women leadership and gender diversity?&amp;nbsp;</strong>I don&amp;rsquo;t think the lesser working period is really an issue any more because the average work engagement for all people, including men has become much shorter. People are much more mobile and changing jobs and careers faster than ever. Women actually possess more of the soft skills and emotional intelligence necessary for effective leadership today. So it is not really a skill issue. The main issue seems to be mind-sets and old, out-dated traditions. By and large, women primarily need to develop the belief and confidence to become a leader - again this means a change in their mind-set.<strong>What makes a good leader? How important is trust to leadership?&amp;nbsp;</strong>You can&amp;rsquo;t just create a master list of traits and start ticking them off. There is not one perfect mould for effective leadership. The real key is to identify where a person is now -what are their strengths and weakness -and then develop an individualised plan to maximize their strengths and to minimize their weaknesses.Everyone can be a leader at some level, and every person needs to further develop his or her leadership ability. The four stages I mentioned earlier are really the only constants in this process. It is an on-going journey for all of us!</body><post-date>Tue, 2017 Oct 17 17:30:42 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Pitney-Bowes-Believes-In-Investing-In-Its-People/11-10-2017-128277</link><title>Pitney Bowes Believes In Investing In Its People</title><categories><category>Employee</category></categories><description>In an interaction with BW Businessworld, Manish Choudhary, SVP, Global Innovation &amp; MD India Operations, Pitney Bowes Inc. talks about the company's hiring intentions and the strategy behind the company ranked as India's top companies to work for</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body><strong>Pitney Bowes has been one of India&amp;rsquo;s Top companies to work for seven times in a row. What has been the strategy?</strong>Our culture of doing the &amp;lsquo;right thing the right way&amp;rsquo; is a key differentiator rooted in decades-long commitment to our clients, stakeholders and communities. Pitney Bowes is a global technology company powering billions of transactions in the physical and digital world of commerce. We began operations almost a century ago as leaders in the physical world of mailing and evolved to become innovators that combine the best of physical and digital solutions to redefine global commerce.As a 100 year-old start-up, innovation and reinvention are a part of our DNA and what&amp;rsquo;s kept us around all these years. Our secret is simple, we invest in our people. At Pitney Bowes, we have a diverse workforce ranging from mechanical engineers to data scientists to quality assurance experts to support functions, and our job is to make sure that everyone has the opportunity to do truly challenging and rewarding work. By providing our people with the best learning and development opportunities, we are able to create a highly engaged, driven and motivated workforce which has been named one of India&amp;rsquo;s Best Employers seven times.<strong>How do you see India as a marketplace and what are you hiring intentions?</strong>We are always looking for bright talented people to join us and continue to hire people working on new technologies who are driven to make a difference in the way businesses conduct commerce. In order to keep pace with changing technological trends and support the burgeoning Indian start-up ecosystem, we launched the Pitney Bowes Accelerator Program in 2014 and have since then mentored 18 start-ups working in areas of customer information management, mobile, data analytics, location-based services, ecommerce management and machine learning.We host regular hackathons and connect with larger developer communities on open Cloud-based platforms. Earlier this year, we held Code Inspire 2.0, a women-only hackathon where more than 2,000 women participated from across India. We are currently hosting the Global SMB Hackathon, targeted at developers around the world to build applications and solutions for potentially more than one million Pitney Bowes clients.<strong>The company has been successful in retaining the best talent. How do you manage to retain the best talent in the organisation?</strong>People are bound to stay if you provide people with great work, an engaging environment and ample opportunities for career progression and growth. Globally we have 14,000+ diverse employees that take great pride in helping clients succeed in the physical and digital worlds of commerce. There&amp;rsquo;s no one thing that keeps people engaged, it&amp;rsquo;s about making sure that people&amp;rsquo;s heart and mind are in the right place and the company is as invested in them as they expect their people to be.<strong>Can you share some insights into any employee appreciation program practised in the company?</strong>We value innovation and reinvention and our appreciation programs nurture this culture. We have Hackathons and Innovation Awards that recognise teams to create business relevant hacks annually. At the end of every year, the best innovative team is recognized through the Innovation of the Year Award.Employees are inspired to hone and enrich their skills. Under the Technical Ladder Program, a specialized career path enables employees to accelerate their careers while leading some of the most critical projects in the organization. We emphasize our client-focused culture with Excellence Awards that recognize people who exemplify our ethos of Client. Team. Win. Innovate.We have a number of programs such as Appreciation Week and Pay-it-Forward that encourage employees to recognize colleagues from different teams and foster cross-business collaboration.<strong>Do you undertake skill development for your employees?</strong>Skill enhancement is the most important factor to stay in a job and is therefore the best bet for companies to retain top talent. Pitney Bowes has a number of programs in place to help employees learn and grow.Our Global Early in Career program is an 18-month mentoring program to help accelerate development of our young talent through a series of structured networking sessions. We have a number of other Learning &amp;amp; Development and Mentoring programs for employees and focussed programs such as Aspire to Inspire, targeted for potential women leaders.We also focus immensely on peer-learning programs to tap into the depth of knowledge possessed by our subject matter experts, enabling them to gradually become effective mentors to younger talent.Pitney Bowes regularly hosts Developer Meets in association with leading industry bodies that bring together tech leaders to speak on current hot topics such as Machine Learning, AI, Big Data among others.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 11 16:19:28 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Creation-And-Application-Will-Bring-Out-More-Talent-In-Students/11-10-2017-128239</link><title>Creation And Application Will Bring Out More Talent In Students</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>The beauty of using technology is the fact that if you are not good at something, the software will help it rectify. Students may no more be afraid of mistakes, because they have an undo button to rewctify the mistakes</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>The human brain thinks verbally and visually, but most of us communicate verbally. If we look at the education system, the need was for people to read and write. Today, all the subjects have become equal, and thus the demand for verbal communication has increased significantly.The beauty of using technology is the fact that if you are not good at something, the software will help it rectify. Students may no more be afraid of mistakes, because they have an undo button to rewctify the mistakes.Rishi Khemka, CEO, MindBox said, &amp;ldquo;MindBox is helping schools through programs to communicate verbally, and visually. Children go to schools, and by the time they finish; they don&amp;rsquo;t remember things, because of the lack of application. You are consuming information, but a visual medium will build life skills, technology helping understand things and correspond them in real world.&amp;rdquo;MindBox has built a whole curriculum from class 1st to 10th, with the idea of curriculum being taught in subjects, and take out topics and create projects using technology tools which could have multiple subjects together, and the faculty can correlate these things to teach the students.Rishi Khemla added, &amp;ldquo;Our focus is on building creators and thinkers rather than only doers. Right now, the focus is on students in schools and impact as many lives as possible. We have worked with Shiv Nadar, and also with state board schools.&amp;rdquo;The affordability of the programs is purely on the investment we have to make on the faculties, and is based on the number of students in each school. The company is currently present in NCR, Bombay, Bangalore, Hyderabad and Chennai.Last year, they expanded into Tamil Nadu at the district level. Now, they are expanding more into Punjab, Haryana, UP and next year into Gujarat, Pune and go deeper into Andhra and Telangana.MindBox has another platform called Design Championship where students can showcase their talent; and this competition encourages students to think out of the box. Design Championship, thus, gives a chance to those talented students to put their skills to use.Khemka added, &amp;ldquo;We touch 20,000 students&amp;rsquo; lives in India and our aim is to reach a million lives. India has 250-260 million students in school, and I want to reach millions of students. We are hoping to 3X this year, and reach our objective by 2022, and then we can take it further.&amp;rdquo;</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 11 12:58:31 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Job-Market-Will-Improve-With-GDP-In-The-Next-2-Years-NIIT-Technologies/11-10-2017-128238</link><title>Job Market Will Improve With GDP In The Next 2 Years: NIIT Technologies</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>In an interaction with BW Businessworld, S. Viswanathan, Chief People Officer, NIIT Technologies talks about the skills that can be imparted in school students making them job ready, and NIIT's role in job market and technology</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body><strong>What has been the company&amp;rsquo;s growth in terms of helping job market, and technology?</strong>With the dramatic shift in the market requirements, there has been significant need for bringing in more technology skills into the Indian IT profession. NIIT Technologies has created opportunities for fresh IT graduates through a completely redesigned entry skilling program to ensure that they can be relevant even, though there has been a big shift in the technology arena from what they have formally learnt.NIIT Technologies has addressed these needs through two independent tracks. The first is in establishing partnerships with providers of technology solutions, like Arago in the area of Artificial Intelligence, to enable technology absorption and adoption; and the aspect has been in building a strong learning ethic amongst the NIITians and making available well-structured training curriculum that enables staff to remain relevant with the changing technology demands.<strong>Education is the root of every working professional. How to create students who are skilled enough to be employed?</strong>The role of technology is growing with each day and this changing dynamic has made the need for right education and training more critical. According to a study by World Economic Forum, 65 percent of children entering primary school today will ultimately end up working in completely new job types that don&amp;rsquo;t yet exist.Considering these significant technological changes, the students who enter the workforce are finding that their knowledge has been rendered inadequate as applied technology has already evolved in the time they spent studying. The results have been evident for almost a decade now as only 7 percent of engineers are employable. In such a rapidly evolving employment landscape, the ability to anticipate and prepare for future skills requirements, job content and the aggregate effect on employment is increasingly critical for businesses, governments and individuals in order to fully seize the opportunities presented by these trends to mitigate undesirable outcomes.It is important for studetns to get diverse, experiential and practical education to adapt with the changing times and stay relevant to be employed.<strong>What skills can be imparted to students from K-12 to prepare them for the changing job demands?</strong>It is important to connect the school environment of the students to long-term job goals and earning potential. Students need to be self-learners who can identify gap in their knowledge/skills and fill in the gaps. The school systems today should develop curriculum that address both content absorption (along the lines of various subjects that connect to higher education) and approach absorption (like Critical Thinking, Collaboration, Curiosity, Creativity).<strong>What are the indicators that decide the health of job market? When do you see the job market improving?&amp;nbsp;</strong>The classical indicators of job market will continue to remain the number of new jobs created in an economy. &amp;nbsp;Another way to look at this is to consider the overall number of jobs that are available to current workforce to evaluate as options to switch. One of the possible misconception in evaluating the IT job market is to count number of jobs in currently known roles, which completely misses the reality of emerging roles that can be in the cusp of IT and non-IT domains.If we are to consider the overall job market then the improvement will certainly start becoming visible as the GDP shows some signs of moving towards the higher single digit, which could be in the next 18-24 months.<strong>Are there any disruptive HR policies that you have adopted recently?</strong>The role of technology in HR has radically changed in the last five years and will continue to evolve at a rapid pace. We have entered the world of cloud in the last few years, where companies started to migrate from in-house software to cloud-based HR solutions, and now we are focusing on &amp;lsquo;Digital HR&amp;rsquo;. One of the initiatives in this direction was the creation of Digital Diary App which enables communication between team members and supervisors in a structured manner.From a policy perspective, some initiatives have been in letting the individuals take ownership for their development and sustained employability, while the organization provides access to curriculum. In some of our businesses we have also brought in significant emphasis on their compensation being tied into their demonstrable skilling.<strong>What are the recent trends in employee engagement? What are your views in retaining the best talent in the organization?</strong>In this age of digital, years of experience is no longer a key criterion for recognizing talent. There are various segments of employees, which co-exist in the organizations today. Old school and millennials bring different set of skills, experience to the companies, and require customized engagement. However, organizations today are turning to technology to create predictive steps to measure engagement levels and correct behaviors in a proactive fashion. Here are some of the key trends that are changing the very face of employee engagement in 2017:<ul><li>Performance Management Technology is critical</li><li>Data Focus approach leading to better understanding of people</li><li>Delayering where hierarchy and bureaucracy are being replaced by agile teams</li><li>Cultural shift to foster high employee engagement.</li></ul>NIIT Technologies is all about people. This is a principle that the Resource Management Group (RMG) at NIIT Technologies has adhered to religiously. To further strengthen our relationship with the employees, it is very important to keep them engaged and motivated, while working collaboratively to achieve their personal and organizational goals. Retention of employees is part of Human Resource management and planning efforts. Hence it is the responsibility of the line managers as well as the management to ensure that the employees are satisfied with their roles and responsibilities and the job is offering them a new challenge and learning every day.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 11 12:54:21 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/India-Is-A-Very-Important-Market-For-AMD-Dr-Kiranmai-Pendyala-Corporate-VP-COO-HR-AMD/11-10-2017-128223</link><title>India Is A Very Important Market For AMD: Dr. Kiranmai Pendyala, Corporate VP &amp; COO, HR, AMD</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>Dr. Kiranmai Pendyala, Corporate Vice President &amp; Chief Operating Officer, HR, AMD talks to BW Businessworld about employee engagement, HR policies and company&#8217;s views about India as a marketplace</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body><strong>How do you see India as a market place and what are your hiring intentions in India?</strong>India is a very important market for AMD &amp;ndash; both as a consumer base for our products and as a center for our R&amp;amp;D work. Currently, we have a team of 1300 plus employees in AMD India, and they are largely engineers. Our engineers are equally distributed between our Bangalore and Hyderabad centers.We hire about 300 people across various levels in a year. Of this at the entry level, the plan is three pronged. We take about 20 students under the Co-op program and about 50 students for our three to six-month internship program. In addition, we recruit about 80 NCG (New College Graduates) straight out of campus. So that&amp;rsquo;s about 150 entry level recruitments. We have tied up with more engineering institutes this year and increased the numbers for Co-op, internship and NCG. So, we are looking at about 200 entry level hiring and another 100 or so lateral hiring.<strong>What policies do you adopt to retain the best talent in the industry?</strong>We firmly believe what our founder, Jerry Sanders said, &amp;ldquo;People first, Products and Profits will follow&amp;rdquo;. This sentiment is ingrained in our DNA. We invest heavily in our employees to ensure they are proud of being an AMDer and get the right opportunities to learn and grow with us.We have a &amp;lsquo;Dual Career Ladder&amp;rsquo; approach to meet the career aspirations of our employees, wherein they can choose individual contributor positions or organizational positions, based on their interest, business need, and their competence. Employees are more engaged when they see that their managers are concerned about their growth and provide avenues to meet their aspirations. The approach also eliminates the promotion of employees to positions they are not suited or aspire for. More importantly, it reinforces the importance of creating a work environment where every employee adds value each, in his/her own way.We also believe that employees must feel invested in our growth. To ensure this, we follow a four-pronged approach:* Sharing the &amp;lsquo;Big Picture&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash; This allows the entire workforce to learn the long-term vision for the company, envisioned by the leadership* Translating and sharing the blueprint of the &amp;lsquo;Big Picture&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; We provide employees a detailed Year-on-Year (YoY) product roadmap and the anticipated RoI (return on investment) that the company aims to make* Divulging the blueprint to various teams &amp;ndash; Teams across various geographies have discussions on market share, expected returns, the competitor landscape and the valued impact of technology innovation in solving roadblocks of tomorrow* Identifying and drafting &amp;lsquo;champions&amp;#39; to lead &amp;lsquo;powerful conversations&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash;This helps us drive the needed change with positive energy by entrusting employees who have a passion for problem solving<strong>How can one make technology more relevant to bridge the skill gap in different professionals?</strong>Re-skilling is an ongoing activity at AMD India and at the very center of our employee value proposition. Close to 40 percent of our existing employees undergo re-skilling to help them adapt and adopt design thinking and state of the art tools and technologies to design, build, and sell our innovative products. This is also critical because India is a R&amp;amp;D hub for AMD.We organize regular boot camps and host trainings under two pillars &amp;ndash; Technical Leadership Programs (TLP) and Leadership Development Programs (LDP), to strengthen the skill sets of both units. In addition to in-class room trainings, employees have always-on, free access to thousands of e-learning programs from SkillSoft and Lynda.com. These allow AMDers to study a variety of subjects at their own pace from project management to communication skills, six sigma, human resources, finance, accounting, sales, marketing, operations, and hundreds of other topics.<strong>What are the recent trends in employee engagement?</strong>Employee engagement practices are changing to keep pace with the changing demographics and psychographics of the millennial workforce. We have to look at innovative ways to source, develop and reward talent. The interventions are happening on two fronts.Firstly, for a generation hooked on to internet and smartphones, organizations are deploying digital tools to create a seamless HR experience and improve organisation communication. We have connected our employees across the globe, irrespective of hierarchy to an internal &amp;lsquo;AMD Connect&amp;rsquo; platform, which allows employees to tell their personal and professional stories via photos and blogs and results in increased productivity, collaboration and trust.Secondly, and perhaps more importantly HR leaders are beginning to rethink the established notions of productivity and loyalty by studying and understanding the aspirations of the modern workforce. We are introducing qualitative feedback which highlights the strengths of an employee while holding the light on the opportunities and the support being offered by the manager, team and the culture, for the employee to further enhance his/ her value at AMD.<strong>How important is work flexibility in rewarding employees other than cash rewards?</strong>When employees are given even a small degree of flexibility at work, the employee has significantly better job satisfaction, stronger commitment to the organization, and most importantly - lower levels of stress.At AMD India, we offer policies such as flexi-time and telecommuting options, as well as encouraging annual vacations. An on-site gym, indoor games, Zumba sessions, a shuttle court, annual sports competitions among various functional teams, as well as regular team outings and celebrations, also add to the fun at the workplace. This ensures that employees are able to attain requisite work-life integration, while being able to innovate, which is a core cultural trait of our organization.<strong>Are there any disruptive HR policies that you have recently adopted?</strong>We believe that none of our employees should have any fear in voicing ideas. It&amp;rsquo;s important for innovation-led companies like ours to facilitate a system where employees believe that every idea has its own value. Without that, no innovation would happen and we would not be able to continue providing cutting-edge technologies to businesses and consumers.At AMD, we conduct Ideathons, where the employees come up with an idea which they can showcase to all major sites across the globe. It helps us in two ways, we get to tap into high potential talent and employees get an opportunity to meet leaders from different business verticals across geographies. We also have AMD Innovation Fund, where employees can present their ideas, proof of the concept and apply for the fund to realize their idea.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 11 11:43:27 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Jobs-In-Telecom-Sector-Under-Scrutiny-Backed-By-Mergers-And-Freebies/11-10-2017-128220</link><title>Jobs In Telecom Sector Under Scrutiny Backed By Mergers And Freebies</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>The sector is burdened with debt of nearly Rs 8 lakh crore and heavy losses due to a slew of freebies which are being given out compulsorily by telecom players to retain their customer base</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Debt- ridden and loss struck telecom sector in India faces more problems of corporate downsizing and which will affect nearly 150,000 direct and indirect jobs in the sector, as per industry estimates.The sector is burdened with debt of nearly Rs 8 lakh crore and heavy losses due to a slew of freebies which are being given out compulsorily by telecom players to retain their customer base.The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) in April had warned commercial banks about loans given to telecom sector companies. The telecom sector is reporting stressed financial conditions and severe cost-cutting measure seems to be the way out.Facing the brunt will be around 20,000-25,000 direct jobs, many of which will be due to planned mergers between incumbent players. Mergers alone will lead to over 15,000 job losses as existing portfolios and profiles are duplicated.However, industry estimates place a far larger number of around 125,000 indirect jobs that will be wiped out due to the turbulence being faced by the sector. An industry analyst told IANS, &amp;ldquo;In the larger scheme of things, with the economy slowing down and most industry sectors seeing flat or negative growth, the impact is going to be &amp;lsquo;telling and bloody&amp;rsquo;, with jobs not being created across sectors, and re-employment becoming a tough task.&amp;rdquo;The government is under stern pressure for slow economic growth and lower than expected job creation, and will further create problems to indulge unemployed people into alternatives. The sector was amongst the top five largest employment opportunity generators in the country some time back, and supported direct employment to over 20 lakh in the country during 2015-16.According to the Annual Report 2016-17 of the Department of Telecommunications, &amp;ldquo;As per some estimates, the mobile industry in India currently contributes 6.5 per cent ($140 billion) to the country&amp;rsquo;s GDP, and employs over four million people (direct and indirect).&amp;rdquo;</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 11 11:28:20 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Jobs-Are-Likely-To-Grow-Till-FY18-Report/09-10-2017-128027</link><title>Jobs Are Likely To Grow Till FY18: Report</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Hiring outlook is expected to improve incrementally over the next six months, largely driven by increase in government spending and stable hiring growth</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Hiring outlook is expected to improve incrementally over the next six months, largely driven by increase in government spending and stable hiring growth exhibited by a few sectors and cities, according to a report by TeamLease Services Employment Outlook Report.As per the report net, employment outlook for the coming six months (October 2017-March 2018) will see an incremental increase of 2 percentage points.According to the report, six of the 18 sectors surveyed have indicated positive hiring sentiment. The financial services industry alone is expected to see a 3 percentage point rise in employment outlook. The report further noted that hiring sentiment continues to be positive among large businesses while small businesses remain pessimistic.The other key sectors seen to experience positive hiring intent are Knowledge Process Outsourcing and Health and Pharmaceuticals. In contrast, the laggards in the coming half year would be construction and real estate, agriculture and agro chemical and travel and hospitality respectively, the report stated.Rituparna Chakraborty, co-founder and Executive Vice-President, TeamLease Services said, &amp;quot;The modest pace at which the hiring sentiment is growing seems to indicate a steadier and stable recovery rather than a temporary spike. In fact, most of the profiles that companies are adding are not just to address the short-term requirement, but to build capabilities indicating the good tidings are here to stay.&amp;rdquo;From a hierarchical perspective, mid-level hiring, which was down in the previous half year is expected to pick up in coming months. The senior level hiring also seems to be on a growth trajectory. However, the entry and junior level hiring sentiment seems to be hit. The report provides a comprehensive overview about the mechanics of hiring, job growth, salaries and their drivers for the period October 2017 to March 2018.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Oct 09 19:26:19 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Non-IT-Professionals-Learning-Analytics-To-Save-Their-Career/09-10-2017-128025</link><title>Non-IT Professionals Learning Analytics To Save Their Career</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Technology and IT companies, given their relative comfort with technologies have been early adopters and have derived maximum benefit from them</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Computing power and bandwidth coupled with the growth of smartphones has enabled large volumes of data to be captured, communicated and stored very easily and cheaply, resulting in the need for big data technologies including big data analytics.The growth in Big Data is posing challenges while at the same time creating opportunities for organizations: challenges in terms of lacking the capabilities and skilled professionals to manage and analyze data, while opportunities in terms of new products and services, product/service customization and personalization, new insights to realize process efficiencies; that Big Data Analytics is enabling.<strong>Sector Mapping</strong>Like with most technologies, there are early adopters, mainstream adopters and late adopters. Technology and IT companies, given their relative comfort with technologies have been early adopters and derived maximum benefit from them.BFSI also tends to be an early adopter given that technology always provided a competitive advantage in finance. Other industries like Manufacturing, Automotive, Pharma, Healthcare and Media are the mainstream adopters and are now aggressively adopting Big Data Analytics. Other industries like Tourism, Agriculture, Hospitality and Education tend to be the late adopters. However, every industry that has adopted these technologies is deriving strategic benefits which will ensure that eventually all of them will.<strong>Importance of Analytics for career</strong>Mohan Lakhamraju, Founder and CEO, Great Learning said, &amp;ldquo;We, at Great Learning, believe that analytics will become a fundamental skill that everyone will have to know to some extent. At Great Learning, we are seeing professionals from many sectors beyond IT, learning analytics. They are safeguarding their career and helping their organization by building analytical capabilities.&amp;rdquo;Data-driven decision making is taking over the heuristic, experience-based decision making that was prevalent earlier, where all the professionals will have to get comfortable with working with data and with data-driven decision making.The IT industry regularly goes through cycles of technological change. This transformation makes some jobs redundant, while creating newer jobs and the IT industry is going through one such phase. This is causing confusion and insecurity amongst IT professionals.Also, new opportunities are opening up for technology professionals in emerging areas such as Analytics, Big Data, Machine Learning, Cloud Computing and Information Security.<strong>Increasing Interest in Analytics&amp;nbsp;</strong>Mohan Lakhamraju &amp;nbsp;added, &amp;ldquo;At Great Learning, we are empowering professionals to take advantage of these trends by up-skilling themselves instead of getting rendered irrelevant by it. In the last 18 months, we have seen a jump of over 300 percent in terms of interest from professionals working in the IT Sector, out of which 70 percent of candidates in our programs are IT professionals.&amp;rdquo;Technological shift will not be restricted to merely the IT sector but every other sector where efficient decision making is the key. &amp;nbsp;Therefore, the nature of jobs in all the sectors will eventually change where all knowledge professionals will have to work with data to varying extents.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Oct 09 19:21:22 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Education-Sector-Will-Grow-At-7-5-To-144-billion-By-2020/09-10-2017-128022</link><title>Education Sector Will Grow At 7.5% To $144 billion By 2020</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Vikas Singh, MD, Pearson India shares his thoughts about virtual international education narrowing gap between upper and lower strata, and skills needed to create studetns skilled enough to be employed</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body><strong>Give me some insights about virtual international education, and will technology help bridge the gap between upper and lower strata in terms of education affordability?</strong>We have recently launched first-of-its-kind Virtual International K&amp;ndash;12 Education in India with International Connections Academy (iNaCA). It aims to help students learn in their own way and at their preferred pace through a personalized and engaging experience that includes various multimedia tools such as enhanced videos, social, adaptive and game-based learning.The teachers personalize lessons, evaluate student progress and provide feedback and assistance through real-time virtual sessions to offer a targeted support based on student learning.International Connections Academy (iNaCA) uses a proprietary web-based platform called Connexus, to provide a complete virtual school experience and to connect teachers and students who are dispersed geographically. The platform delivers the online content anytime and anywhere, facilitates teacher-student and student-student interaction both synchronously and asynchronously, and allows students around the world to participate together in online activities from robotics to poetry club.The ability to connect excellent teachers with students everywhere and provide engaging, effective content online may be emulated by those focused specifically on affordable education in India.<strong>Some NGO&amp;rsquo;s are working to take education to the farthest parts. Do you have some strategies to help the underprivileged children and nurture the talent from every nook and corner of the country?</strong>Pearson IndiaCan Vocational operates several vocational training centres for youth in rural areas to train them on basic skills, enhance their knowledge base and provide relevant employment opportunities. Pearson IndiaCan Vocational is playing a pivotal role in planning, designing, and implementing vocational skill development courses, in partnership with the Ministry of Rural Development (MoRD), Government of India.Young Indians from disadvantaged and underprivileged backgrounds have been motivated to undertake skills training and education post which they are provided employment in various companies.The programs are designed keeping in mind the specific requirements of the students coming from economically weaker sections. It entails:1. Working with local community to understand the challenges of youth2. Career counselling for students to make the; best choices3. Customized residential and non-residential training programmes4. Training encompassing modules on trade-specific skills, IT and soft skills5. Stay and travel support to students during training6. 75% assured placement above minimum wages7. Post-placement support and counselling<br><strong>Education is the root of every working professional. How to create students who are skilled enough to be employed?</strong>Though the quantity of universities, colleges and programmes are going on increasing in the country, the lack of quality education still persists. The curriculum that is offered by institutes of higher education in India hardly keeps pace with industry demands. Therefore, dire need to foster a shift from an input-centric pedagogical approach to an outcome focused, learner-centric approach, to impart holistic learning.India needs a focus on outcome-based measures to skill its workforce for the evolving industry trends. There is an urgent need to understand the kind of jobs that the industry requires and create specific skill sets accordingly.Assessment is a potent tool which can not only measure the learner&amp;#39;s performance, but can also modulate the overall teaching strategy with the help of analytics. We are making a big shift from just &amp;quot;Assessment of Learning&amp;quot; to incorporating &amp;quot;Assessment as Learning&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Assessment for Learning&amp;quot;, &amp;nbsp;in a more pro-active and pedagogical manner, facilitating learning capacities.<strong>What skills can be imparted to students from K-12 to prepare them for the changing job demands?&amp;nbsp;</strong>Focus of education in schools must be on infusing and developing innovation skills among students as opposed to filling them with knowledge. For this to happen, there is a need to break away from standardized testing processes that is at odds with creativity. Some of the ways in which innovation can be encouraged at school level:1. Encouraging students to explore possibilities and find their own answers to questions rather than following the teacher-driven lessons for better imagination, observation, judgment and reasoning skills.2. Acknowledging and rewarding students for their ideas and innovation3. Adoption of technology-driven models such as &amp;ldquo;Virtual or blended learning classrooms&amp;rdquo; to improve access as well as basic education standards in the country.4. Designing curriculums that enable students to meet with demands and challenges of future workplace.<strong>What has been the company growth in terms of technology?</strong>Pearson is world&amp;rsquo;s leading learning company. Our products are researched, expertly developed and continually improved to ensure that they deliver the best possible learner outcome that enable learners around the world to make progress in their lives. Our focus has always been on digital programmes and learning and we continue to deliver technology enabled products that are accessible and flexible for learners. Some of the innovations from Pearson have been &amp;ndash;MyPedia -&amp;nbsp;giving teachers and other faculties the opportunity to develop their students&amp;rsquo; digital skills, integrating technology in education helps them stay engaged.iNaCA (International Connections Academy) - iNaCA provides a flexible world-class curriculum for students studying in classes up to class 12, aiming to help students learn in their own way and at their preferred pace through a &amp;nbsp;personalized and engaging experience.Digital Learning Solutions &amp;ndash;&amp;nbsp;Students are eager to participate in engaging rigorous digital learning programmes and we partner with institutions to implement Digital Learning Solutions.PTE Academic -&amp;nbsp;It offers the fastest score reporting in the market, with test takers receiving their results typically within five business days. It provides simple and seamless experience for the user which makes this process less stressful for applicants and assessors.<strong>What is the target the company is looking at and the strategies to be adopted to reach the target?</strong>Pearson has a formidable presence across all segments of education. We are looking at the next generation of courseware and products coming in, which will help fuel further growth for the company. Digital courseware will be one big step moving forward. The second is getting into distance education and we are partnering with the best in the world to bring it back to India. Some of them are giving us content relevant to the Indian context which we then customise to suit the needs of the Indian market. The third is strengthening people&amp;rsquo;s English language.<strong>How is the job market in the education sector and what are your hiring plans?</strong>India has the largest school going population and higher education infrastructure in the world. According to a report, the sector is pegged at $ 100 billion and will grow at CAGR of 7.5% to $ 144 billion by 2020. It is expected that employment opportunities will continue to grow in this sector for the next two decades.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Oct 09 19:12:45 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Fintech-Success-Will-Bring-Better-Stability-and-Security-To-Customers/06-10-2017-127752</link><title>Fintech Success Will Bring Better Stability and Security To Customers</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>The sheer number of meetup groups, accelerator programmes, conferences and job openings dedicated to a relatively new industry like fintech is phenomenal</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Fintech also has a hype pattern like every other industry and it is perhaps going through the peak hype phase at the moment. The sheer number of meetup groups, accelerator programmes, conferences and job openings dedicated to a relatively new industry like fintech is phenomenal.The number of startups being launched in cities like London and countries like India every week is huge. However, there is still room for investments into the sector to go dramatically higher and much higher investments are expected to be coming in from Asia, Africa, Latin America and the Middle East. These geographies will likely be the largest markets for fintech in 5 years&amp;rsquo; time.Future of FintechFintech expert Devie Mohan believes, &amp;ldquo;Fintech will see a larger amount of collaboration in the future. There will be much more meaningful collaboration between banks and fintechs, fintechs and academia, as well as between the fintechs themselves. Most global banks have a very strong desire to work with fintechs and they will continue to work with fintechs based on specific use cases, solving specific challenges.&amp;rdquo;Devie added, &amp;ldquo;Finally, the go-to-market and success strategies of a fintech startup will become more linked to the macro environment and the developments from regulatory bodies and governments. The industry will start seeing a much higher level of regulation and this could affect the amount of innovation seen today, while offering better stability and security to the consumers.&amp;rdquo;Banks and Fintech start-upsDevie Mohan who has been ranked as the 6th most influential voice in the FinTech industry shares her views on bank and fintech start-ups.She shared, &amp;ldquo;Banks do what they do best and fintech startups do what they do best. I don&amp;rsquo;t think banks can ever become a fintech.&amp;rdquo;There are 3 major areas where a bank can benefit by bringing in technology<ul><li>Offering a better service to customers, thus improving customer retention and engagement</li><li>Creating and launching innovative and better offerings, thus bringing in a wider group of target customers</li><li>Creating operational efficiencies within their existing infrastructural and IT environment.</li></ul>Technology can play a strong role in making all of these objectives happen for banks. The only problem is that banks cannot, and should not, adopt a new technology for the sake of technology. The technology element should be invisible in whatever they create and launch.Increasing investmentBanks will continue to invest in fintech startups, or working closely with them to find new and interesting collaborative opportunities. Banks around the world had invested $ 5 billion in fintech startups by 2015. Just last year, this amount was $ 9.5 billion, indicating banks&amp;rsquo; interest in the space is increasing exponentially every year.Talking about women leaders gaining prominence, she added &amp;ldquo;A large majority of entrepreneurs in the fintech industry have come from the banking industry, having identified certain gaps in the industry and leaving to solve that gap. The gender or diversity representation in fintech is thus very similar to that of the banking industry. I am sure for both male and female entrepreneurs, fintech is one of the largest and strongest digital industries to play in today.&amp;rdquo;</body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Oct 06 15:23:49 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Bad-Days-Ahead-Income-Inequality-To-Rise-Causing-More-Social-Tension/04-10-2017-127516</link><title>Bad Days Ahead: Income Inequality To Rise Causing More Social Tension</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>Joblessness, which has been deteriorating in the last few years mixed with income inequality, will impose a higher risk of social tension</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Income inequality in the country is likely to worsen due to the government&amp;#39;s inability to create jobs, warns a report by financial institution Ambit Capital. The report also added that joblessness, which has been deteriorating in the last few years mixed with income inequality, will impose a higher risk of social tension.Income inequalities have been rising systematically since the 1980s. Ambit said the bottom 50 percent of the country&amp;#39;s population accounts for only 11 percent of the national income, while the top 10 percent accounts for 29 percent, which is a big difference.Even though per capita income stands at Rs 121,138, it is shockingly low at a mearge Rs 26,192 for the bottom 50 percent of the total population. This is the same as a citizen of Madagascar and lesser than a citizen of Afghanistan which has per capita income of Rs 36734.Just 13 million of the population or the top 1 percent of the population has a per capita income of Rs 35,16,276, which is comparable to Denmark&amp;#39;s and is higher than the per capita income of Singapore at Rs 34,67,886.<a href=""><iframe src="//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/18D6K/2/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" width="100%" height="250"></iframe></a><br>Noting that the government&amp;#39;s inability to create jobs is likely to intensify inequalities, the report says that the increasing demand for jobs under the MNREGA scheme is expressive of the deteriorating jobs potential particularly in the lowest economic strata. The weakness in blue-collar jobs is also revealed by the stagnant rural wage growth.The report warned that a combination of joblessness and inequality leads to an increase in social problems, such as a surge in crimes.The report says, &amp;quot;Our own experience shows that states like Bihar and Uttar Pradesh with significantly lower per capita income than national average and high degree of inequalities, have very higher levels of crime rates than other states.&amp;rdquo;</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 04 16:01:32 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Lack-Of-Basic-Business-Plan-Stalling-HR-Processes/04-10-2017-127513</link><title>Lack Of Basic Business Plan Stalling HR Processes</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>Organisations have witnessed a rise in HR initiatives in the past 18 months, although about 85 percent of executives said this has not achieved the set return on investment</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Human Resources are the business drivers in today&amp;rsquo;s time when the disruptive business environment is driving companies to transform their human resources functions. However, Indian organisations remain stalled with nearly 60 percent saying they do not even have a basic business case in place for HR initiatives.The data is in line with global findings, which show 59 percent of surveyed executives saying that they do not have a basic business case for putting in place key HR processes, as per the findings of the KPMG HR Transformation Survey 2017.Organisations have witnessed a rise in HR initiatives in the past 18 months, although about 85 percent of executives said this has not achieved the set return on investment.The survey was conducted on 887 executives from 48 countries between February and April 2017, with representation from 27 industries across Asia-Pacific, Europe, North America, Middle East/Africa and Latin America. From India, 109 executives were surveyed.Vishalli Dongrie, partner in BPS-People and Change, KPMG in India, said, &amp;ldquo;Most respondents are currently involved in HR transformation. Overwhelmingly, most of them have a modest and traditional view of projecting HR transformation with systems and processes. Despite the urgency shown by CEOs, transformation is still not stirring in the context of supporting a business strategy or helping a company meet its business objectives. So, going forward, the manner in which HR addresses transformation will be pivotal.&amp;rdquo;HR technology spends, in 89 percent of the cases in India, remained the same or rose across organisations since last year. The survey found that the biggest areas of investment expected for India, in 2017, are talent management, HR data and analytics, on-boarding and payroll. Most of the executives said they believe that process and cognitive automation will drive the way HR services are offered in their respective organisations.Talent acquisition, on-boarding, learning and talent management are the areas where respective HRs are likely to aim and enhance in the next three years.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 04 15:55:53 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Employees-Wish-To-Get-Their-Dream-Job-In-India/04-10-2017-127512</link><title>Employees Wish To Get Their Dream Job In India</title><categories><category>Employee</category></categories><description>A large part of the workforce considers India to be their dream destination for work, while a major part of the workforce still trying to get their dream job in the country</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Professionals have been going abroad for a better job and quality of life for a long time and this scenario could change very soon.India has emerged as the dream destination for most job-seekers with nearly 60 percent job seekers looking for their aspirations in the country, according to a TImesJobs survey. &amp;nbsp;The major part of the workforce wanted their dream job in India, thus making the country a dream destination for most job-seekers.The survey conducted among 1,100 job-seekers in the country found out that engineering is still the dream job profile for men; while women yearned to become a doctor or be in the medical profession.Out of the total male workforce, nearly 25 per cent job-seekers wanted to be a doctor or medical professional, 20 per cent want to be in the Information Technology (IT) industry, 15 per cent would like to become chartered accountants and 10 per cent are keen to become a lawyer.Keeping aside the eagerness for women to become doctor, nearly 25 per cent want to be Chartered Accountants (CA), 20 percent would like to be in IT, 15 per cent wanted to become engineers and 10 per cent would like to be part of the human resource (HR) profession.Overall, IT continues to attract the majority with nearly 35 per cent job-seekers willing to work in the industry followed by healthcare and manufacturing sector for about 30 per cent each. Nearly 25 percent job-seekers wanted to be in telecom industry, and another 25 percent are interested to be part of the automobiles sector.Out of the total professionals, about 55 percent job-seekers felt they are not currently working in their dream profile. Of these, 65 percent men felt their current role is not their dream role while 75 percent women job-seekers said the same.About 70 per cent job-seekers haven&amp;#39;t still been able to get a job in a company they aspired to work, while 25 per cent job-seekers said they have given up on the idea of their dream jobs, it added.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 04 15:53:10 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/TCS-Subsidiary-To-Inherit-1000-Employees-From-Lloyds-Banking-Group/04-10-2017-127510</link><title>TCS Subsidiary To Inherit 1000 Employees From Lloyds Banking Group</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>The LBG said the move was part of a push to develop better digital services for customers with insurance, pensions and investment products</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>The Lloyds Banking Group (LBG) of UK has told its staff that it will be moving 1,000 jobs to Diligenta, a subsidiary of tech giant Tata Consultancy Services(TCS). The LBG said the move was part of a push to develop better digital services for customers with insurance, pensions and investment products.Lloyds said, &amp;ldquo;The new platform will make managing heritage products simpler and more efficient for LBG customers. The staff will be able discuss the non-contractual arrangements with Diligenta over coming months.&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;The wholescale transfer of 1,000 Lloyds Banking Group staff to Diligenta is nothing short of a betrayal of these workers,&amp;rdquo; said Rob MacGregor, national officer at Unite union.Rob MacGregor, national office at Unite Union said, &amp;ldquo;The bank&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;sale&amp;rsquo; of its committed Scottish Widows and Clerical Medical staff represents contempt for long serving and skilled employees.&amp;rdquo;The union fears the transfer will affect staff pension benefits and other non-contractual Lloyds perks once they join Diligenta at existing offices under a Transfer of Undertakings (Protection of Employment) arrangement.MacGregor added, &amp;ldquo;Unite is calling on Lloyds to reconsider this shameful deal and do the right thing by its staff who have worked hard to ensure the business is the success it is today. The message from the Lloyds Banking Group is loud and clear and appears to be &amp;lsquo;so long, thanks for your efforts, you work for them now&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;A Scottish Widows spokesperson said, &amp;ldquo;Lloyds Banking Group has partnered with Diligenta to enhance its service proposition for customers with heritage life, pensions and investment products through a new digital platform.&amp;rdquo;Diligenta already successfully manages more than 11 million life and pension policies in the UK on its end-to-end policy administration platform.The Lloyds had returned to private ownership in May after the UK government sold the last of its stake in the bank.TCS subsidiary Diligenta describes itself as a transformational business process services provider, with an approach to simplify inherited operations, business processes and IT architecture through transformation.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 04 15:48:48 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Job-Market-Showing-Signs-Of-Recovery-Online-Hiring-Sees-Growth/04-10-2017-127506</link><title>Job Market Showing Signs Of Recovery; Online Hiring Sees Growth</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Good to see the job market showing signs of recovery. The JobSpeak index for August has shown a Y-o-Y growth of 1 per cent</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Online hiring activity registered just 1 per cent rise in August over the year ago period, but eight of the 13 cities surveyed showing positive growth indicate signs of recovery, says a report by Naukri JobSpeak index for August which stood at 1,851, registering just 1 percent growth from August last year.Major important industries like auto, construction and BFSI saw a growth of 11 per cent, 9 per cent and 5 per cent respectively in August this year.V Suresh, Chief Sales Officer Naukri.com said &amp;quot;Good to see the job market showing signs of recovery. The JobSpeak index for August has shown a Y-o-Y growth of 1 per cent.&amp;quot;Suresh further added that the recovery seems to be spread across geographies with 8 of the 13 cities surveyed showing positive growth. The volatility in the market is likely to continue for few more months before it moves north.Of the 13 key cities tracked, eight cities recorded an increase in hiring activity in August 2017 as against last year. The index for Delhi, Mumbai, Hyderabad and Chennai grew by 4 per cent, 1 per cent, 8 per cent and 5 per cent respectively while Bengaluru saw a dip of 3 per cent in hiring activity.Industry wise, BPO/KPO jobs went up by 7 per cent while jobs in the IT-software services sector saw a dip of 6 per cent in August over last year.In terms of experience, senior management roles with experience between 13-16 years saw a 6 per cent growth in August this year as compared to year ago period.Jobs for entry level jobseekers having 0-3 years&amp;#39; experience increased by 3 per cent while junior level roles for jobseekers with 4-7 years of experience witnessed a 1 per cent dip in hiring, the report added.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 04 15:44:30 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Start-ups-Will-Create-Maximum-Jobs-Through-IoT/04-10-2017-127504</link><title>Start-ups Will Create Maximum Jobs Through IoT</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>In an interaction with BW Businessworld, Ketan Kapoor, co-founder and CEO of Mettl, online talent management firm, highlights the factors for the downfall of the IT sector and inspects the situation, talking about the skills in demand. (Edited Excerpts)</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body><strong>What can be done to revive the IT sector?</strong>Between the rapid rise of automation and Indian tech service companies, new jobs continue to be created, although at a slightly slower pace. These new jobs, however, require higher skills and therefore, reskilling is crucial to the industry. With net hiring in the industry continuing, it is on its way to createnearly three million jobs by 2025, according to Nasscom.Tech employees need to pick up new skills related to the automation domain as these new technologies have a rapidly growing market across the world. Companies also need to integrate reskilling into their learning and development program in order to equip employees with newer skills and prepare them for greater job roles.<strong>Is there a need to bridge the gap between Industry demands and supply of professionals?</strong>Yes definitely. The gap in the academic curriculum and the industry requirements has been the biggest issue for the IT/ITeS industry in India. The lack of hands-on experience among IT professionals is a major reason for the slow growth in the sector. A viable solution to this problem is that companies must ensure that new hires are the right fit for the organization&amp;rsquo;s needs and possess the required technical skills to fulfill a specific job role. Companies can conduct certification and training programs to equip new hires with relevant skills and make sure they meet their true potential from the first day itself.In addition to clearing the gap out, we should keenly observe the universities across the expanse of our country to renew and revamp their instructional courses according to the growing need. Peeling away from age-old techniques of teaching and analysing, these premier institutions should start with making cloud-based assessments as their primal target because they are being adopted across the world in giving better feedback to prospective candidates and students.<strong>What can help the IT sector revive its glory days?&amp;nbsp;</strong>IT industry has seen several changes in technology and has reinvented itself every time. In the process, engineers learned new code to realign their skills with the industrial developments and achieve professional growth. However, in the more recent past, technology has undergone tectonic shifts, bringing down the sector growth to single digits.Tech companies today want IT professionals to be well-versed with technology like machine learning, augmented reality, virtual reality, artificial intelligence, and Internet of Things. In order to keep up with these evolving market needs, IT companies need to adopt a more practice-centric approach to training employees. Moreover, while traditional IT services will continue to be in demand, companies need to focus on providing assessment services which are data-driven and competency mapped digital technology services.&amp;nbsp;<strong>What skills can help a graduate get a job?</strong>The rapidly evolving IT sector demands a range of skills from professional to meet the ever-increasing demand for digital services. Knowledge of data science and analytics, Angular JS, React JS, Java, Ruby, Python, Scala are among the top skills in demand at present. In addition, new-age technological tools such as machine learning, IoT, AR, and VR are in huge demand as digital services companies as well as equipment manufacturers look to tap into the younger consumerdemographic segments. Professionals can acquire greater conceptual knowledge and more practical experience with access to coding simulators, and to equip themselves with the right skills and stay ahead in the job market.<strong>How to make technology more relevant to bridge the skill gap among different professionals?</strong>Within an organisation, technology can be effectively leveraged to identify the skill gaps, make appropriate training recommendations, and provide regular feedback to employees through AI-based tools. Graduates and professionals can train or up-skill themselves with certification programs on online training platforms. These platforms can work with job portals and corporate recruitment agencies and networks to find the right talent with the relevant skills.<strong>Should graduates look forward to other sectors for employment?&amp;nbsp;</strong>IT is relevant across all industries, be it banking, healthcare or any other service sector. IoT, for instance, will bridge the gap between different verticals, creating an environment of greater interconnectivity among sectors with IT and digital technology being the common link.IoT has huge potential for job creation and most of these will be generated by start-ups which have created solutions in diagnostics, sports wearable, etc. The IoT space is booming in India with about 65 percent of Indian start-ups working on it. The government is also looking at ways to lay out regulations for machine-to-machine (M2M) communications. Once that happens, the sector will truly take off, and job opportunities will follow for those who have the necessary technical knowledge and practical skills.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Oct 04 15:39:19 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/How-to-manage-HiPOs-effectively-/27-09-2017-127101</link><title>How to manage HiPOs effectively </title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>Organisations look forward to invest in the development of the right set of employees and for this they need to identify high potential employees and develop them as future leaders.</description><author>Sunil Munshi</author><body>Every business today has a perfect blend of talent wherein some of the employees are HiPos and rest of them are the regular ones, and it takes an apt balance of these to run the organisation. Today, what differentiates an efficacious organisation from others is the way they manage their value pools, more specifically, the &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; talent or High Potential employee pools. Now, the focus has been shifted towards evaluating the potential &amp;amp; capabilities of employees rather than their performance. Organisations look forward to invest in the development of the right set of employees and for this they need to identify high potential employees and develop them as future leaders.While sourcing Hipos is a critical task, equally important is their channelization in the right direction and to make the most of their capabilities. The goal thus is to attract, develop and retain high potential employees having appropriate skills, commitment and capabilities, required to meet existing and future organizational needs. Given the current backdrop of rapidly changing global scenario and technology advancements, there is a rising demand for leaders who can succeed in today&amp;rsquo;s uncertain, complex, volatile, and ambiguous business environment.<strong>Investing in the right people</strong>How much so ever cliched it may sound, people remain the most critical asset of any organization. In the realm of sales and marketing, employees are the first face that customers interact with. Thus, a high potential employee can turn the tables altogether when it comes to driving revenue. Probably this is the reason why one of the industry leader of an eminent technology firm produced an off-beat legend, creating a culture of &amp;lsquo;Employees First Customer Second&amp;rsquo; with a firm belief that an organisation can achieve success by following this mantra. While many glaring evidences and blue-ocean thoughts around employee engagement shout-out loud, sometimes even Management and HRD leaders fail to take cognizance of this critical issue. That&amp;rsquo;s why this is vital to not only identify, but also to nurture and retain employees with high potential.<strong>Nurturing the HiPos</strong>In an era where talent landscape is markedly competitive, HiPo employees should be the top most priority for any organisation otherwise if they don&amp;rsquo;t take care of them, their competitors soon will. Let us look at couple of organisational attributes for managing the HiPos effectively:<strong>Trust Showcase</strong> &amp;ndash; This is the foremost requisite of all. While an organisation may value a high potential employee, however, till the time, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t showcase complete trust on their potential, their decisions etc. it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say that those talents will stick around for long. Praising someone and trusting some are two different things and in case of Hi-Pos, both form an essential factor.<strong>Timely Rewards and Recognitions</strong> - Recognising that the employees have potential helps them thrive better. Providing regular rewards and recognition can instill a sense of great self-esteem, positive reinforcement, and higher job satisfaction in them.<strong>Leadership and Management Support</strong>: Thriving in a competitive corporate set up is not a cakewalk. Besides HR specialists to facilitate HiPos, involvement of the leaders and immediate managers is essentially crucial to make their journey worthwhile.<strong>Engagement and Training</strong>: HiPos feel stress with corporate politics around them, that is why it is hard to hold on to them as they usually have several desired options available outside. The executive staffing firm Challenger, Gray, and Christmas reports that 42% of the employers are worried that other companies will steal their top talent. Therefore, for re-strengthening your HiPos&amp;rsquo; mental and emotional system, it is a must to keep them engaged, which in turn, will impact their &amp;ldquo;discretionary effort&amp;rdquo; for higher performance. Also, after re-strengthening their mental and emotional system, it is equally important to provide constructive feedback and throw bigger challenges, supporting them with continuous coaching to unleash their maximum potential.<strong>Work-life balance</strong>&amp;ndash; Needless to say, but HiPos are a hot commodity at all levels today! Probably their high-potential makes them exposed to the expectation level which is sometimes difficult to meet and they end up messing up their personal life with the professional formalities. Therefore, it is critical to ensure the aspects of work-life balance of the High Potential employees as well to keep maintaining their productivity at par.<strong>Challenges and strategies to overcome these challenges:</strong>Having a robust pipeline of HiPos talent gives competitive advantage to an organization. However, due to increasing challenges of hefty work culture, it has become difficult to engage and retain them. This is quite evident as per a study by the Corporate Executive Board, which shows that the turnover rate of high potential employees is 30%. Now the question arises how should we strategise to reduce this low engagement-high turnover ratio and how can we ensure retaining these valuable assets? Obviously, there is no cookie-cutter approach for creating a successful retention strategy. Basically, you can-not predict what works somewhere else to manage them, will also work for your organisation too. For instance, employee&amp;rsquo;s future aspirations, training and development gap along with the leadership and middle management&amp;rsquo;s handling gap are some of the prevalent challenges that hampers the performance of high potential employees. However, since we know that organisational culture majorly impacts the engagement-retention level, below mentioned are two key focus areas to enhance the productivity of HiPos:The art of communication is the language of leadership: Leadership plays a major role in terms of best managing any high potential talent. Since, everything trickles down from leaders to HRD to managers and ultimately to subordinates, it&amp;rsquo;s a continuous process wherein a perfect synchronisation of all of them is important.Succession planning is the Key: Many organisations focus all planning on their C-level employees. Focusing all your attention only on getting people to the top spot might be paralyzing since in no time leaders can change, markets can change, and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find and sustain an enduring proposition without an enduring stream of talent. Therefore, creating a healthy talent pipeline signifies development at all levels.<strong>It&amp;rsquo;s a marathon of continuous efforts</strong>This is now evident that identifying candidates and tossing development their way is just not enough. We need to continuously track and evaluate their progress. Performance evaluations and timely recognition prove to be some invaluable tools, giving an insight into how those identified future leaders are performing, and how valid that assessment continues to be. In a nut shell, we see that these days the organisations which identify their Hi-POs, find ways to engage and retain them while leveraging the most from their potential &amp;ndash; are the ones who are able to progress far better in comparison to the rest, towards their strategic goals.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Sep 27 17:04:08 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/HR-will-switch-from-a-transnational-to-advisory-role/27-09-2017-127092</link><title>HR will switch from a transnational to advisory role</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>In the recent past there has been an uptake in the digital HR. However, one should not get carried away and believe that digital will replace human/ face to face interactions</description><author>Prateek Shukla</author><body>With advancing technology, the model of HR departments is also changing. Businesses are fast racing towards making their HR digital to recruit in a better and efficient manner and this also helps them in better employee engagement. In an exclusive interview with BW People, Shiv Agarwal, ABC Consultant speaks about digital HR, new approach for talent search, online job applications and more.<strong>Do you feel that the concept of digital HR is becoming a top priority among employers?</strong>Yes, in the recent past there has been an uptake in the digital HR. However, one should not get carried away and believe that digital will replace human/ face to face interactions. Digital is an enabler and will help the companies in managing their processes better and help scale inefficiencies.<strong>Technology is fast advancing; it plays an increasingly important role in approaching the talent search &amp;amp; hiring process. How do you adapt your services to the latest tech trend?</strong>Technology has democratised data so the role of consultant has/ needs to evolve beyond sourcing. To be able to better serve our clients, we at ABC Consultants, have recently started using Bullhorn software. Bullhorn is a staffing and recruitment software that allows companies to enjoy greater productivity by streamlining the entire recruitment process and ensuring proper candidate management.In addition to this, ABC Consultants has recently also acquired a significant stake in QuezX, which is India&amp;rsquo;s leading online recruitment aggregator that enables companies to hire rapidly across functions and geographies. Apart from a Series A investment in QuezX, we have merged our online business unit - HeadHonchos - with the operations of QuezX. The combined entity now serves all three stakeholders in recruitment &amp;ndash; employers, recruitment agencies and candidates. It is India&amp;rsquo;s first B2B2C recruitment marketplace with a unique database of over four million professionals, doubling every six months. HeadHonchos will now extend its offerings across all levels of professionals.<strong>Online job applications have begun to gain traction. Is it difficult to select appropriate talent without physical interaction?</strong>Online job applications have been in vogue for some time now. It is becoming easier to select candidate without having any physical interaction, thanks to the technology. It has become easier to source candidates online from the vast data pool that is available at your disposal. One can conduct video interviews, there are plenty of online assessments that one can conduct to test their expertise on certain specific skill sets. Also, one can perform reference checks online.<strong>The use of data leveraging HR technology tools is at an all-time how. How HR departments leverage data analytics to decide employ ability&amp;nbsp;of a person?</strong>Employability of a candidate is still very much a decision that HR Managers are making on their own, however a few companies have started using Big Data Analytics to facilitate the decision making process. A few companies like Unilever have started using AI based technology to screen candidates; others like P&amp;amp;G and American Express are still evaluating the technology. Overall, use of analytics to access employ ability is still in its nascent stage and we need to understand its potentials before it becomes main-stream.<strong>With increasing use of AI, what do you see as the future of HR departments?</strong>HR will continue to remain relevant but rather than having a transactional role, it will switch to being a more advisory role.<strong>Your clients are across various verticals, so how do you decide on the necessary skill sets required for different organizations?</strong>At ABC, talent hiring on an national platform across 10 offices in India and over 500 employees divided in 25 specialized industry verticals, ensures that each client receives truly customized, innovative and in-depth service solutions from us. We recognize that each industry has its own nuances and therefore, each of these verticals are headed by Industry domain specialist consultants who come with extensive experience and are backed not just with a proactive team but also an unparalleled &amp;lsquo;live&amp;rsquo; database and network built over 48 years of ABC&amp;rsquo;s presence in India.<strong>Tell us about your methods of post recruitment follow-up?</strong>A post-joining hand-holding and follow up is an imperative part of the hiring process. We remain actively in touch with both our client and the new joinee to ensure a smooth transition. Open communication and feedback remains a key component of this process.<strong>Job creation has been abysmal in the last few years. How does it impact your business?</strong>According to us, despite the economic slump, India Inc. has held the ground very well. Things are looking positive in the post-GST world, and we are expecting business to look up in the months and hiring to pick up pace in most sectors in the time to come.<strong>You cover markets of Middle East / GCC, Africa, Far East and South / South East Asia. How is it different from the Indian market?</strong>We do provide services for markets like Middle East/ GCC, Africa and even South East Asia and it is an important and growing part of our business. Our global sourcing vertical addresses the needs of our client based out of India. Technology plays a big enabler in this regards and we are living in a virtual world wherein we have tools such as LinkedIn, Skype and video conference that we can effectively use.<strong>MSMEs are one of the biggest job providers in our nation. How do you cater them with the right talent given their limited pay package?</strong>One of the biggest recruitment challenges for organisations is hiring at junior levels without compromising on quality and speed. Yet, the natural tendency of most recruitment firms is to focus on senior &amp;amp; middle management recruitment services. Currently, this segment is highly fragmented with various small to mid-sized recruitment firms occupying this space with no one being able to provide the reach and scale to fully satisfy client needs. Head Count, as a division of ABC Consultants, was established in 2010 to provide high quality recruitment solutions that address volume hiring needs at junior management levels for large corporate. We operate on a key account management model where, because of the volumes with each client, we dedicate resources on a full time basis to serve a client.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Sep 27 16:16:53 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Over-10-Percent-Indians-Lie-In-Their-Resume/26-09-2017-127025</link><title>Over 10 Percent Indians Lie In Their Resume</title><categories><category>Employee</category></categories><description>Out of the total people giving wrong information, almost 10 percent of them report faking about completing a course, 5 percent report about fake universities, and the majority of discrepancies, almost 50 percent are found in documents submitted by the candidates

</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>More than ten percent of the Indians lie about their education, residence and criminal records in their resume while applying for jobs, as per the data collected by global screening agency, First Advantage.Out of the total people giving wrong information, almost 10 percent of them report faking about completing a course, 5 percent report about fake universities. However, the majority of discrepancies, almost 50 percent are found in documents submitted by the candidates.Purushotam Savlani, SVP and Managing Director of First Advantage said, &amp;quot;In India, background screening is done only by IT industries, finance firms and banks. Off late, we have also seen traction developing in sectors like hospitality and manufacturing.&amp;quot;However, this number is quite low when compared to foreign countries which can be due to the weak checking mechanism.Background screening is a concept in India, but isn&amp;#39;t followed much which results in people giving fake information. According to the data collected by the agency, the discrepancy versus verified percentage for 2011, 2012 and 2013 was at 10 per cent. In 2014 it had risen to 10.5 per cent, while in 2015 it has further risen to 11.6 per cent. However, it fell to 11.1 percent in 2016 and further to 10.6 percent, in the first half of 2017.He added, &amp;quot;There are various checks while verifying the resume of a candidate, like education, past employment and criminal history. Educational discrepancies are taken very seriously, especially in fields like IT and Finance because if a person lies about having a skill that he/she does not have, technical work, which needs to be done by a specialist will suffer.&amp;quot;</body><post-date>Tue, 2017 Sep 26 17:39:21 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/GST-To-Boost-Job-Creation-In-The-Manufacturing-Sector/26-09-2017-127023</link><title>GST To Boost Job Creation In The Manufacturing Sector</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Implication of GST has been complex and has had a short term impact on hiring across organizations and industries. However, industry feedback suggests that within this quarter situation is bound stabilize and hiring shall resume</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Manufacturing sector has contributed less than 15 percent to the GDP thorough the years, and has contributed merely less than 12 percent to the employment generation. However, TeamLease expects GST implication to create formal jobs in the sector as the manufacturing outlook will increase in the upcoming quarter. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;The sector has huge potential to make this growth huge and employment generation. GST implication will bring simplification in tax calculation, availability of input credit, reduction of cost of production, improved cash flows, ease of registration and lower cost to customer, and all this is expected having a positive impact on Jobs.Implication of GST has been complex and has had a short term impact on hiring across organizations and industries. However, industry feedback suggests that within this quarter situation is bound stabilize and hiring shall resume.According to IIP (Index of Industrial Production), the industrial production has witnessed a 1.2 per cent growth in July from a contraction of 0.2 per cent in June indicating a growth in the manufacturing sector. In fact, as per IIP data eight out of the twenty three industry groups in the manufacturing sector have shown positive growth during the month of July 2017.GST implementation needs to be backed by on ground actualisation of the vision Make In India, smart cities, ease of doing Business, skilling India and a healthy regulatory regime to create the volume of formal jobs needed for a 13 million youth who are joining the workforce every month.Consumption is seen growing across industries and TeamLease expects additional 50,000 additional jobs to be created in the next 5 months to cater to the increased demand on account of the festival season alone.</body><post-date>Tue, 2017 Sep 26 17:31:12 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Increasing-need-of-Cyber-Security-professionals-in-the-BFSI-industry/26-09-2017-127008</link><title>Increasing need of Cyber Security professionals in the BFSI industry</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>In the year 2016-2017, global incidents exposed a large security gap in the industry. Unfortunately, there are no patterns in these compromises and cyber-crime experts are required to shield the humongous data in the digital domain.</description><author>Mamta Wasan</author><body>Digitization has changed the world as we see it. It has become a win-win situation for customers and BFSI institutions, because it offers convenience to the former and cost effectiveness and scalability to the latter. Because of scalability, a large number of users are getting added to the workforce each day reaching mammoth proportions on some of the platforms. This, however, has exposed the industry to new vulnerabilities. Because digital barriers are in a virtual medium, a small compromise in the systems, can lead to larger ramifications as in the examples below.In the year 2016-2017, global incidents exposed a large security gap in the industry. Unfortunately, there are no patterns in these compromises and cyber-crime experts are required to shield the humongous data in the digital domain. We need more investment in people, technology, and processes to mitigate the growing threat vulnerabilities.Few examples of attacks that have targeted the BFSI industry in in the year 2016-2017 are mentioned below:1. An ATM attack happened in October 2016 due to the presence of ATMs-specific malware in the systems of one of the well-known Payments Service Provider2. WannaCry ransomware attack occurred in May 2017, exploiting vulnerability in Microsoft SMB protocol. This created havoc for the BFSI sector. This was despite the fact that Microsoft released patches one month before the attack occurred.3. Petya ransomware attack occurred in June 2017, again exploiting Microsoft SMB vulnerability.4. Hacking of ATMs occurred in June 2017, due to Chinese malware Rufus exploiting ATM&amp;rsquo;s running on the Windows XP operating system. Microsoft had stopped releasing patches for this for the last few years.These events highlight system vulnerabilities &amp;amp; share the increasing thereat the industry faces, both the user and the vendors. There is thus the need for more Cyber Security Experts in the BFSI sector and this is constantly increasing. This industry needs to come forward and invest more in training with an intelligence based approach to cybersecurity, to mitigate the shortage of skilled talent.In general, FIs follow common defensive measures which include technology for monitoring and detecting intrusions or abnormal behavior. This approach however, does not cover newer threats such as third-party vulnerabilities, insider&amp;rsquo;s attacks, geopolitical risks and other emerging attacks.So, in addition to investment in security products, the BFSI industry requires talent with a new mindset and new skills in the form of Cyber Security experts. These experts will help organizations in:1. Identifying potential threats via research to take action proactively.2. Validating historical data and other information about threats and to find its relevance to organization.3. Prevent the impact of future attacks or incidents.4. Able to provide information required to make critical and strategic business decisions.5. Provide training and timely information to internal and external stakeholdersCybersecurity needs to be integrated with business&amp;mdash;which includes services, products, digital investments, technology, processes and people for the successful growth and profit of the business. Failure to integrate this critical function will expose an organization to high risk in the long term.Over past few years, the demand for cyber security professionals has grown at a faster pace. There is talent lacuna in the market and this can be seized as an opportunity for career aspirantsVarious Cyber Security Certification courses needed by the industry are available online. These are from basic to advanced levels. Some suggested courses are:1. Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)2. Global Information Assurance Certification (GIAC)3. Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP)4. Systems Security Certified Practitioner (SSCP)5. Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)This is a field that is going to continue to grow. It is both challenging and paying and can open the doors to an exciting global career.</body><post-date>Tue, 2017 Sep 26 15:31:29 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Secrets-To-Boost-Employee-Morale/25-09-2017-126940</link><title>Secrets To Boost Employee Morale</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>Recognizing employees for doing the job right increases the likelihood that they will continue to do so, enabling them to make a dramatic impression on the company</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Positive reinforcement is the easiest way to maximise employee happiness, effectiveness and engagement. Building employee&amp;rsquo;s strengths is far more effective than criticizing their weaknesses.Recognizing employees for doing the job right increases the likelihood that they will continue to do so, enabling them to make a dramatic impression on the company.<strong>Pallavi Jha, Chairperson and Managing Director, Dale Carnegie Training India told BW Businessworld</strong>, &amp;ldquo;Make it clear that there is no cap on praise, acknowledgment and appreciation, be a role model by openly acknowledging good work and accomplishments. Consistent communication is necessary in order to keep your employees engaged. Employees whose managers hold regular meetings with them are much more likely to be engaged as compared to their counterparts. &amp;nbsp;A great manager makes his or her team feel comfortable and cared about consequently, engaged employees will go the extra mile to give back.&amp;rdquo;<strong><u>Talent management</u></strong>Demand for talented workforce is growing with the rise of gig economy. Flexible timings are becoming increasingly popular, which helps in reducing employee burnout, reduces stress, while saving time and money.Pallavi Jha added, &amp;ldquo;Flexible timings increase employee morale and commitment, reduces absenteeism and attrition, and increases the organization&amp;rsquo;s ability to recruit outstanding employees. With flexible timings becoming more and more common, organizations are hoping to attract younger, brighter and higher-quality talent than ever before.&amp;rdquo;Leaders need to uphold team morale. Their confidence will convince the team that obstacles are natural, and their focus should remain on the greater goal. If you exude calm, the team will follow suit. Employee hiring and engagement shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an issue as long as the team believes in your mission, vision and goals.<strong><u>Recognition is important</u></strong>Recognition programs should be a part of any organization&amp;rsquo;s culture. Take every opportunity to broadcast the value created by your team members. Make their accomplishments visible internally and externally. If they coached a colleague, ensure the HR head knows. If they went out of their way to assist in solving a problem in another departmentdespite it not being a part of their job role, congratulate them with pomp.About recognition at Dale Carnegie, Pallavi Jha added, &amp;ldquo;Peer-to-peer recognition increases employee engagement and at Dale Carnegie India, we implement it in the form of a monthly recognition program where employees nominate one another whilst stating why each nominee deserves recognition for their recent performance. With this, we&amp;rsquo;ve created an organization of people who support and enable one another to accomplish the best.&amp;rdquo;</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 25 17:49:35 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Top-FMCG-Companies-To-Work-For/25-09-2017-126937</link><title>Top FMCG Companies To Work For</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>With so many companies involved, Jobbuzz recently derived a list of top FMCG companies in India on work-life parameters through employees&#8217; survey. Here are top FMCG companies for employees</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Fast Moving Consumer Goods (FMCG) companies are a major employer in India with an estimated 15-20 per cent workforce being employed in the sector. A large workforce needs proper management of work conditions and work-life balance.With so many companies involved, Jobbuzz recently derived a list of top FMCG companies in India on work-life parameters through employees&amp;rsquo; survey. Here are top FMCG companies for employees:<strong><u>Hindustan Unilever Limited</u></strong>One of the oldest operational FMCG company in India, HUL has its core business of food, beverages, personal care and cosmetics among others.Employees believe it is a great company that looks after its employees, with good pay cheque and other benefits. About 66.4 per cent of the employees believe they are paid at par with the market standards.<strong><u>Dabur</u></strong>Another FMCG major which operates in various product categories, such as hair care, oral care, healthcare, skin care, home care and foods, specializing in Ayurveda. It is the oldest and one of the fastest growing FMCG companies.Nearly two-third of the employees surveyed by JobBuzz believe the work flexibility schedule provided is great.<strong><u>Nestle</u></strong>Nestle specialises in dairy products, food and coffee, along with baby feeding products. A popular brand in India, Nestle has wide range of products in various categories such as milk products, beverages, infant foods, chocolates &amp;amp; confectionery.Employees feel competitive salary, strong global presence, great products make a strong case for the company as a good employer. Cares about its employees, company growth, good work-life balance and career growth opportunities are ample.<strong><u>ITC</u></strong>The core business of the ITC is hotels, personal care, tobacco, food items etc. With more than 10,000 employees, good colleagues, work environment and high wages make it a good company for the employees.Everyone is genuinely smart, enthusiastic, and friendly. The culture is casual, good team environment, people are passionate, intelligent and driven.<strong><u>Parle Agro</u></strong>Another FMCG company indulged in food items and beverages. Quality of work is the major reason employees love to prefer this company. 20 percent people prefer the company due to its brand name, 16 percent for salary and 14 percent for work-life balance.Employees feel it is just an amazing place full of smart and passionate people. A very positive with constructive culture, Parle encourages work-life balance, professional development, and a great culture.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 25 17:22:41 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Microsoft-Committed-To-Growth-Of-Indian-Start-ups/25-09-2017-126936</link><title>Microsoft Committed To Growth Of Indian Start-ups</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>The company recognises that India's entrepreneurial landscape would aid robust economic growth in the coming years and was committed to contributing to the Indian start-up growth story</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Microsoft India has believes in the Indian start-ups and has assisted more than 4,000 start-ups in India, conducting skill training for 30,000 people along with 26,000 teachers while working with several state governments and non-profit organisations during FY17 in India, as per its India Citizenship Report.The company recognises that India&amp;#39;s entrepreneurial landscape would aid robust economic growth in the coming years and was committed to contributing to the Indian start-up growth story. The company has supported and guided the start-ups with programs like BizSpark and Microsoft Accelerator.Microsoft has trained over 8,124 teachers under Project Shiksha, impacting 361,000 students across Tamil Nadu, Rajasthan and Madhya Pradesh.BizSpark is a Microsoft initiative, is aimed at supporting early stage start-ups. More than 100 Indian start-ups were selected under the BizSpark Plus program in 2016-17 which helped them grow their customer base.Microsoft Accelerator empowered start-ups on their journey to build great companies, working with market-ready start-ups and provide the tools, resources, connections, knowledge and expertise that they need to become successful companies.The Microsoft Cloud Accelerator Program served to accelerate the adoption of services such as Microsoft Azure and transform business and governance in a mobile-first and cloud-first world.Under Project Saksham, the company has conducted trainings for over 3,307 educators across 123 universities. These faculty members have, in turn, trained 1,126 of their peers. The company has trained over 661 teachers across 21 universities in FY17.In line with government&amp;#39;s Skill India vision, the company brought Predictive Analysis and Machine Learning technologies to education, healthcare and agriculture in partnership with several state governments.The company&amp;#39;s cloud-first solutions have improved processes, productivity and mobility, in order to accelerate India&amp;#39;s digital transformation. Microsoft Philanthropies has invested over $ 10 million in technology to transform the way non-profits deliver impact in India, offering educational opportunities to the next generation.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 25 17:17:44 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Emotional-technological-and-survivor-quotient-makes-one-employable-/25-09-2017-126906</link><title>Emotional, technological and survivor quotient makes one employable </title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>A testimony to the success of these initiatives is our Employee Engagement scores where the satisfaction rate for Women employees is 2% higher than men and 15% higher than the industry norm.</description><author>Himani Chandna</author><body>Ingersoll Rand&amp;rsquo;s global Chairman and CEO, Michael W. Lamach, has joined more than 150 of America&amp;rsquo;s leading CEOs in a pledge to cultivate diversity and inclusion in the workplace through the CEO Action forDiversity &amp;amp; Inclusion. Shirin Salis, vice-president of human resources at Ingersoll Rand in India told Himani Chandna of BW People that she is driving diversity at workplace through the hiring plans. Excerpts: &amp;nbsp;<br><strong>Which are the areas where you are planning to hire?</strong>Ingersoll Rand hires primarily for functions like sales, service, operational excellence and engineering, IT at different levels. We at an organizational level are open to hiring diversity for any of these functions if the candidate has the ability to perform the job and willingness to learn.<br><strong>What is the top skill set that employers demand these days?&amp;nbsp;</strong>Broadly there is a huge demand for mobile development, cloud computing, statistical analysis and data mining, digital marketing, UI designing, network and information security and storage management, PR and communications, public policy and international relations.While the professional skills are in demand, strong communication skills and analytical ability are additional elements that add to the repertoire of a candidate. These are some skill sets for which the demands are ever increasing and will continue to grow. Not just technical skills but emphasis is also greatly laid on soft skills of a person.&amp;nbsp;<strong>Apart from the skills, what are the qualities that makes an employee more employable?</strong>To be truly employable, new hires today, need to understand the market and acquire skills that are in demand. We believe that in addition to knowledge and skills, what employees need today, in order to thrive in this changing environment, is 3 different abilities &amp;ndash; emotional quotient, technology quotient and the survivor quotient. While technology quotient means the ability to understand, use and converge technologies for better advantage, survivor quotient indicates a mindset about how to do more with less, and the ability to put solutions together with whatever is available, rather than waitfor large resources. &amp;nbsp;In addition to these, soft skills such as interpersonal skills - the ability to effectively communicate vertically and horizontally within the organization is a needed trait. Along with that knowledge of cultures - this is important because most multinational companies seek employees who can work comfortably across different cultures.<br><strong>What are your achievements on gender diversity front? What is the female to male ratio on top level and what are the targets?</strong>At Ingersoll Rand we have been relentless in integrating diversity and inclusion into the fabric of our culture and have undertaken a number of initiatives. The company has long been committed to building a progressive, diverse and inclusive environment where people of all backgrounds are treated with respect, and currently offers resources designed to engage and support a workplace welcoming different points of view, and where employees feel empowered to discuss tough issues at work.Diversity and inclusion are embedded throughout the company&amp;rsquo;s practices &amp;ndash; from business strategy to talent and organizational practices to its 2020 Sustainability Goals including clear targets to foster an inclusive and diverse workplace. The company&amp;rsquo;s sustainability goals also align with the United Nations sustainable development goals for reduced inequalities and gender equality. In addition to this, earlier this year Ingersoll Rand joined dozens of companies in the Paradigm for Parity coalition to bring gender parity to its corporate leadership structure by 2030.<br><strong>What are the initiatives that you have taken to promote diversity?</strong>Some of our initiatives include driving representation of female employees at key positions within Ingersoll Rand. &amp;nbsp;We have a set target for diverse slates for mid to senior roles in our professional and leader bands. Driving diversity in our hiring plans by providing equal opportunity to people from all regions, communities, religion, economic backgrounds, philosophy and sexual orientation. Celebrating diversity through cultural celebrations across the organization. We have also launched employee resource groups for gender and generational diversity.A testimony to the success of these initiatives is our Employee Engagement scores where the satisfaction rate for Women employees is 2% higher than men and 15% higher than the industry norm.<br><strong>What are the policies to retain woman talent?</strong>Indian women have demonstrated their caliber in domains of science, technology, engineering and production excellence at all levels from the shop floor to the C-suite and this continues to grow. We ensure utmost support and flexibility for expecting mothers and try to diffuse stress at work as much as possible. That way we ensure that our women employees are with an organization which cares for their well-being and helps them get back to work post pregnancy with ease.From a development perspective, we have a Women&amp;rsquo;s Leadership Program run by our global enterprise which is a multi-month and a multi-format (online and classroom learning, coaching and mentoring, and action learning) learning journey that includes a wide range of resources and tools designed specifically to address the leadership needs of women. The program is designed to enhance the visibility of women leaders with senior management, deepen their leadership skills, clarify their ambitions and support them to realize their full potential.&amp;nbsp;At Ingersoll Rand we also conduct hiring drives specifically focused on hiring women employees. Besides this, we have instituted a diversity forum by creating a number of employee resource groups (ERG) and one such ERG is the Ingersoll RandWomen&amp;rsquo;s Network (IRWN) that aims at creating an environment within Ingersoll Rand that values, attracts and cultivates diverse talents of leaders including women, in a way that has a profound and positive impact on the employees, the organization and our industries worldwide. IRWN creates business opportunities and build leadership competence in women through networking, advocacy, skill and professional development, coaching and mentoring and community outreach. IRWN members are change agents to help maintain position Ingersoll Rand&amp;rsquo;s position as an employer of first choice; and to help each employee reach her/his career potential.<br><strong>How many people you are planning to hire in coming two to three years? What is your current headcount?</strong>Ingersoll Rand&amp;rsquo;s India headcount is close to 2000 employees. As per company policy, we do not share future hiring plans.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 25 13:56:41 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Machine-To-Machine-Communication-Will-Bring-Jobs-CEO-Mettl/22-09-2017-126789</link><title>Machine-To-Machine Communication Will Bring Jobs: CEO, Mettl</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>However, despite being overcrowded, IT is still applicable across all industries, helping transform businesses acting as a common link</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Job market is facing a grilling time and the jobs are far and few. Between the rise of automation and Indian tech service companies, new jobs continue to be created, although at a slightly slower pace. However, these new jobs require higher skills and therefore, reskilling is crucial to the industry.Given the crunch time, job market is further expected to fall by 30-40 percent in the manufacturing sector compared to last year, according to TeamLease Services Ltd.However, despite being overcrowded, IT is still applicable across all industries, helping transform businesses acting as a common link.Ketan Kapoor, CEO &amp;amp; Co-founder, Mettl believes the sector is set for revival and jobs will take off soon. He told BW Businessworld, &amp;ldquo;The IoT space is booming in India with about 65 percent of Indian start-ups working on it. The government is working to lay out regulations for machine-to-machine (M2M) communications. Once that happens, the sector will truly take off, and job opportunities will follow for those who have the necessary technical knowledge and practical skills.&amp;rdquo;The gap in the academic curriculum and the industry requirements has been the biggest issue for the IT/ITeS industry in India. The lack of experience among IT professionals is a major reason for the slow growth in the sector.Companies need to ensure that new employees hired meet organisation&amp;rsquo;s needs and possess the required technical skills for the job role and can conduct certification and training programs to equip new hires with relevant skills and make sure they meet their true potential.Ketan adds, &amp;ldquo;A more practice&amp;ndash;centric approach will immensely help software companies in employee training. Moreover, while traditional IT services will continue to be in demand, companies need to focus on providing assessment services which are data-driven and competency mapped digital technology services.&amp;rdquo;The rapidly evolving IT sector demands a range of skills from professional to meet the ever-increasing demand for digital services. Knowledge of data science and analytics, Python, Scala are among the top skills in demand at present.Additionally, new-age technological tools such as machine learning and IoT are in huge demand as digital services companies as well as equipment manufacturers look to tap into the younger consumer demographic segments.</body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Sep 22 12:27:26 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/By-Third-Quarter-Of-Current-Fiscal-Job-Market-Set-To-Revive/21-09-2017-126741</link><title>By Third Quarter Of Current Fiscal, Job Market Set To Revive</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>With all the macroeconomic parameters being favorable the economy has bottomed up. GDP growth figures will significantly improve in the coming quarter</description><author>Gopal Krishna Agarwal</author><body>The job market has not to be seen only in light of NSO employment data but also include self-employment opportunities created with entrepreneurship development. The job market has significantly undergone change with new set avenues being created with technological advancement and changed economic scenario. The data with regards to jobs have to be looked from a different perspective.With all the macroeconomic parameters being favorable the economy has bottomed up. GDP growth figures will significantly improve in the coming quarter. Government investment over the period has increased many folds, basically in infrastructure development.PM&amp;rsquo;s concerted efforts; to revive stalled projects through the PRAGATI initiative has helped many held up projects. These are creating a lot of demand in the economy propelling private investment as well. Projects like bullet train, which catalyze growth, are seeing the light of the day.Modi government focus on improving manufacturing sector and make India, a global manufacturing hub is important. Globally employment generation primarily emerge from this segment.New forms of employment is being generated with different skills. We have to see the results of developing self-employment and entrepreneurship. Youth is waking up to the requirement of different skill sets where new opportunities are emerging exponentially like a wireless network, data scientist, data architect, artificial intelligence, automobile engineer, 3D technician, cyber security expert etc.Even aggregators like Uber and Ola and E-commerce business are giving new working opportunities. People are being trained in new skills. They are leaving traditional occupations behind. Government efforts on skilling and entrepreneurship development like 5 crore mudra loans and stand up, startup ecosystem is working well. We have reached the third rank in global start-up ecosystem.With corruption and black money under check, transparency and online system of doing business under the new GST and the digital economy regime, ease of doing business (EODB) has gained tremendous momentum.World Bank has recognised twenty economic reforms of Modi government and are ready to be considered in next EODB ranking. We are expecting significant improvement in next the ranking. Nomura has also estimated that our GDP will grow at 7.1% YOY basis.All this is showing positive sentiments and by the third quarter of current fiscal, the job market is going to go up significantly and is already showing signs of improvement.</body><post-date>Thu, 2017 Sep 21 18:35:28 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Software-Developer-Job-In-Highest-Demand-Aspiring-Minds/21-09-2017-126722</link><title>Software Developer Job In Highest Demand: Aspiring Minds</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>According to employability assessment firm Aspiring Minds' Skill Map report; software developer role has the highest demand of 9.74 per cent, followed by sales profile at 8.17 per cent and customer service roles at 6.53 per cent</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Software development, sales, business management and marketing related jobs are currently the most desirable jobs in the Indian job market, as per the employee assessment report by Aspiring Minds.Aspiring Minds, the global leader in employability assessments, recently released the Skill Map &amp;ndash; India, showcasing demand for different job roles and skill sets in India.Aspiring Minds analyzed more than 10 lakh jobs openings spread across the country and matched them with 90 job skill sets, spanning cognitive and soft skills.Commenting on the report, Himanshu Aggarwal, CEO &amp;amp;co-Founder, Aspiring Minds said, &amp;ldquo;Skill Map &amp;ndash; India is a system that reports current job and skill demand. As India transitions its demographic dividend to a 21st century workforce, skill mapping is a key in determining where to invest our efforts and capital. The government skill ecosystem including NSDC, state skill missions and rural development efforts, can use this alarming information to choose the right areas to invest their capital and efforts.&amp;rdquo;<strong><u>Top skills in demand</u></strong><br><strong><u><a href=""><iframe src="//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/pJc2m/1/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" width="100%" height="229"></iframe></a></u></strong><strong><u>Top skills in demand</u></strong>The analysis unveils that top eight enviable skills and traits include 1 soft skill, 4 cognitive skills and 3 personality traits. English Comprehension has topped the chart with 18.71 percent demand. This signifies that English language communication is a much-needed skill across job sectors. A fairly high demand is observed for deductive (11.66%) and inductive (8.56%) reasoning. Out of the personality traits, Agreeableness tops with a demand of 6.42 percent.<strong><u>Demand share of job roles &amp;ndash; State wise</u></strong>On ranking states on the basis ofavailable open positions, Maharashtra bags the top position with 19.72 percent of total open positions in India. Delhi NCR comes in 2nd at 16.99 percent followed by Karnataka at 16.03 percent. Jobs in Maharashtra, Delhi NCR, Karnataka and Tamil Nadu put together form close to 65 percent of open positions across India.<br></body><post-date>Thu, 2017 Sep 21 16:17:24 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/How-IoT-Is-Transforming-Indian-Job-Market-/20-09-2017-126650</link><title>How IoT Is Transforming Indian Job Market
</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>The government is working to lay out regulations for machine-to-machine (M2M) communications. Once that happens, the sector will truly take off, and job opportunities will follow for those who have the necessary technical knowledge and practical skills</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>One sector which has been the most affected in the weak job market and evolving technologies, it is the IT sector. Skill demands are changing rapidly and job growth has been slow, merely 5-6 percent.<strong><u>Job Opportunities</u></strong>Although being overcrowded, IT is still relevant across all industries, including banking and healthcare. IoT will bridge the gap between different verticals, creating an environment of greater interconnectivity among sectors with IT and digital technology being the common link.Ketan Kapoor, CEO &amp;amp; Co-founder, Mettl shared, &amp;ldquo;The IoT space is booming in India with about 65 percent of Indian start-ups working on it. The government is working to lay out regulations for machine-to-machine (M2M) communications. Once that happens, the sector will truly take off, and job opportunities will follow for those who have the necessary technical knowledge and practical skills.&amp;rdquo;<strong><u>Reforms to be addressed</u></strong>Between the rise of automation and Indian tech service companies, new jobs continue to be created, although at a slightly slower pace. However, these new jobs require higher skills and therefore, reskilling is crucial to the industry.He added, &amp;ldquo;The gap in the academic curriculum and the industry requirements has been the biggest issue for the IT/ITeS industry in India. The lack of hands-on experience among IT professionals is a major reason for the slow growth in the sector.&amp;rdquo;Tech employees need to pick up new skills related to the automation domain with technological advanced markets across the world. Companies also need to integrate reskilling into their learning and development program to prepare them for redefined job roles.<strong><u>The way forward</u></strong>Companies need to ensure that new employees hired meet organisation&amp;rsquo;s needs and possess the required technical skills to fulfill a specific job role. Companies can conduct certification and training programs to equip new hires with relevant skills and make sure they meet their true potential.Tech companies today want IT professionals to be well-versed with technology like machine learning, augmented reality, virtual reality, artificial intelligence, and Internet of Things.Ketan Kapoor added, &amp;ldquo;In order to keep up with these evolving market needs, IT companies need to adopt a more practice-centric approach to training employees. Moreover, while traditional IT services will continue to be in demand, companies need to focus on providing assessment services which are data-driven and competency mapped digital technology services.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;<strong><u>Evolving demands</u></strong>The rapidly evolving IT sector demands a range of skills from professional to meet the ever-increasing demand for digital services. Knowledge of data science and analytics, Python, Scala are among the top skills in demand at present.Additionally, new-age technological tools such as machine learning and IoT are in huge demand as digital services companies as well as equipment manufacturers look to tap into the younger consumerdemographic segments.</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Sep 20 18:31:14 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/-NoJobs-In-India-PM-s-Promise-Of-1-crore-Jobs-Annually-Far-From-Reality/20-09-2017-126615</link><title>#NoJobs In India: PM&#8217;s Promise Of 1 crore Jobs Annually Far From Reality</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Job market is facing a grilling time and the jobs are far and few. Job creation has fallen to a 8-year low level with only 1.35 lakh jobs been created between January-December 2015

</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Prime Minister Narendra Modi is far from fulfilling his promise of creating 1 crore jobs annually. And this could well turn out to be his biggest challenge for 2019 elections.Modi came to power 3 years ago after promises of job creation, skill development and reducing inequality among the masses.Job market is facing a grilling time and the jobs are far and few. Job creation has fallen to a 8-year low level with only 1.35 lakh jobs been created between January-December 2015, according to the labour ministry.Given the crunch time, job market is further expected to fall by 30-40 percent in the manufacturing sector compared to last year, according to TeamLease Services Ltd, putting a question on the &amp;lsquo;Make In India&amp;rsquo; scheme.Telecom and allied services, and energy are the two sectors that intend to hire the most, followed by hospitality, banking, insurance, travel, BPOs and automobiles. The opportunities and risks (in the above-mentioned sectors) could shift over time. Businesses that foresee and act on those shifts first will drive the competitive advantage in the coming months, as per the ManpowerGroup.While automation is being accused of making some jobs redundant, it can also create new kinds of jobs. It is now more about finding creative ways to exploit and deploy promising new technologies.Skill development has been talked about a lot for creating jobs and self employment. However, National Skill Development Corporation (NSDC) is able to place only 50 per cent of the total people it train&amp;mdash; which shows the clear difference between inculcating skills and inculcating employable skills.Data on NSDC, sourced from a Right to Information appeal, published by media reports, reveals that less than half of the candidates trained under NSDC got employment. Out of the candidates trained in 2016-17, just 48.4 percent candidates got jobs, while just 46.9 percent got jobs in 2015-2016. Even after indulging in skill development, employment remains a concern.<br><a href=""><iframe src="//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/0aR3V/1/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" width="100%" height="219"></iframe></a><br></body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Sep 20 15:54:27 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Indians-Get-Two-Third-Of-the-Total-Work-Visas-From-UK/20-09-2017-126580</link><title>Indians Get Two-Third Of the Total Work Visas From UK</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>British deputy high commissioner in Chennai, Bharat Joshi said, &#8220;I think the relationship with India is no secret. India is one of the key destinations. About two-thirds of all work visas globally issued is to Indians, which is a huge number.&#8221;</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>United Kingdom wants to see more global trade and more investments and will be looking for more partners to support that.British deputy high commissioner in Chennai, Bharat Joshi said, &amp;ldquo;I think the relationship with India is no secret. India is one of the key destinations. About two-thirds of all work visas globally issued is to Indians, which is a huge number.&amp;rdquo;On dampening investments from India after UK comes out of the EU, he said, &amp;ldquo;No, it is the opposite. We are seeing bigger investments. TVS Logistics (TVS Group) has employed more than 4,000 people and they are expanding. They are continuing to expand. We have a lot of energy travelling in both directions.&amp;rdquo;Students from South India are increasingly applying to study in the United Kingdom, which has seen a 9 percent jump last year compared to previous years, as per the data from high commission.The number of applications from south India which were flat two years ago, grew by 9 percent last year, Joshi said.Bharat Joshi shared in a conference, &amp;ldquo;Last year, it went up by 9%. Students have started to understand much better what the UK system is.&amp;rdquo;Elaborating further, he told that applications were processed from five states - Kerala, Tamil Nadu, Andhra Pradesh, Telangana and Karnataka.There has a constant increase in visit visas being issued to Indians. He added, &amp;ldquo;What we have seen is that quality of students applying to United Kingdom universities has improved.&amp;rdquo;Around 4.14 lakh visitor visas were issues for the FY 17. Of the total visitor visas issues, 11,700 visas comprised of student visas and 5,000 short term study visas.On the impact of Britain exiting the European Union, Joshi said, &amp;ldquo;The UK government is clear that once we leave the European Union, United Kingdom will become a signal for fair rules based trade system.&amp;rdquo;</body><post-date>Wed, 2017 Sep 20 11:41:16 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Diary-of-a-Woman-Leader-Sakshi-Malik/19-09-2017-126531</link><title>Diary of a Woman Leader :Sakshi Malik</title><categories><category>Work Life Balance</category></categories><description>Success for me is not the awards, prize money or the admiration. Success is my own capability to do better and explore myself as a player.</description><author>Aradhana </author><body><span style="font-size: 24px;">S</span>akshi Malik is an Indian freestyle wrestler. At the 2016 Summer Olympics, she won the bronze medal in the 58 kg category, becoming the first Indian female wrestler to win a medal at the Olympics and the fourth female Olympic medalist from the country. BW People&amp;#39;s Aradhana takes insight into diary of a woman leader.&amp;nbsp;<strong>What do you do to motivate yourself when you are feeling low?</strong>The journey of a player is not very easy and happy going, as it seems. We go through a lot of performance stress, as we have to perform not only for us but also for the people who believe in us. <em>&amp;#39;The Secret&amp;#39;&amp;nbsp;</em>film is my secret of motivation. It helps me to regain energy and momentum.I like to be in positive company; hence, I keep visiting my hometown in Haryana whenever I get time.<strong>Whose advice do you seek when you are in dilemma?</strong>My husband is my best friend. We were in relationship for 4 years before getting married. He knows me better than I know myself. Whenever I am in dilemma whether personal and professional, I discuss with him and we solve the mystery together.<strong>What is the one basic quality that a leader must have?</strong>Self-dedication is important of all. If we cannot lead ourselves, we cannot lead others. Recognize your qualities and polish them every day.<strong>What is the meaning of success for you?</strong>Success for me is not the awards, prize money or the admiration. Success is my own capability to do better and explore myself as a player. However, I admire the love of the people but I move on very easily from the limelight and focus on my next goal.<strong>What was the best decision you took in your life?</strong>To take up wrestling as a profession was best of all. I loved to play since I was in school. In the beginning, I used to participate in all games. Then, one day, I saw a picture of a woman wrestler in the papers. I liked her in the wrestling costume so much that I told my parents that this was what I wanted to be. In my initial days, I was charmed with the perks of being a player; good food and different places to visit in the world. Now, I understand the real game.<strong>What has been the highest point of your life?</strong>When I got the medal in Olympics, I was happiest in life. Nothing can replace the feeling of winning medal in Olympics.<strong>What was the lowest point of life? How a leader should cop up with such situations?</strong>Losing my grandmother had a lot of impact on my mind. However, my family and friends helped me in that phase. One should seek to others in such situations instead of escaping and accumulating the stress.<strong>It is often said that early marriage acts as a break in career. What is your viewpoint?</strong>That is traditional thinking. I do not even feel that I am married. Nothing can stop if one is determined enough. If your partner is supportive, you do more than you were doing earlier. My priorities are clear and my husband understands that.<strong>Anything on your wish list apart from winning the gold medal...</strong>I am very fond of travelling but I do not get time to take holidays. I would love to travel around world and eat at different places.</body><post-date>Tue, 2017 Sep 19 16:34:39 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Indian-Job-Market-May-Witness-Positive-Hiring-In-Third-Quarter/19-09-2017-126508</link><title>Indian Job Market May Witness Positive Hiring In Third Quarter</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>India's job market has had a few rough quarters as hiring activity has slumped and there have been reports of layoffs by major IT companies at the start of the year. However, job seekers can expect better opportunities in the coming months</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>India may witness a positive stride towards job opportunities, after facing slump in almost all the industry sectors. &amp;nbsp;India&amp;#39;s job market has had a few rough quarters as hiring activity has slumped and there have been reports of layoffs by major IT companies at the start of the year. However, job seekers can expect better opportunities in the coming months, according to the ManpowerGroup Employment Outlook Survey for October-December quarter.Out of the 5005 employees&amp;rsquo; surveyed, 24 per cent of the employers forecast an increase in staffing levels. Hiring pace would remain slow compared to July-September last year, despite hiring prospects showing an improvement of 4 per cent.The expected rebound in hiring will make India the third most optimistic market for skilled professionals behind Japan and Taiwan, the ManpowerGroup survey said.The Outlook in India has rebounded slightly from the prior quarter when Indian employers reported the weakest forecast since the survey started in 2005. Industry sector forecasts remain mostly weaker than year-ago levels, but improve by varying degrees in most sectors in a quarter-over-quarter comparison.The highest job growth in the fourth quarter is expected in the Services, Transportation and Utilities sectors. The services sector is going to be the biggest job market and will increase its hiring by 23 per cent in the December quarter, showing a good improvement from the previous quarter, where it had seen a 15 per cent increase.Employers in the Wholesale &amp;amp; Retail Trade sector expect a slight decline of 2 percentage points, the survey showed.Employers in all the four regions of the country are optimistic of increasing staffing levels, with the strongest labor market anticipated by employers in the North, who reported a Net Employment Outlook of +27 percent. In the south, employers expect a favorable hiring pace outlook of +20 percent, while good monetary gains of 15 percent are anticipated in the West. However, the most concerning regional outlook of +7 percent is reported in the East.</body><post-date>Tue, 2017 Sep 19 14:58:02 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/-GST-is-unlikely-to-help-improve-the-IT-export-market-says-Narayana-Murthy-/18-09-2017-126440</link><title>'GST is unlikely to help improve the IT export market' says Narayana Murthy
</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>If your entrepreneurial dream has crashed, get up quickly, dust your knees and start working again, Murthy advises. </description><author>Himani Chandna</author><body>N R Narayana Murthy&amp;rsquo;s spoke to BW People&amp;rsquo;s Himani Chandna at the first floor of his Jayanagar-based office Catamaran Ventures. Catamaran is a proprietary, sector-agnostic, family office that invests in inspirational early stage and growing companies in India and overseas. He spoke on range of issues apart from sharing his personal life experiences including the failed entrepreneurial venture.If your entrepreneurial dream has crashed, get up quickly, dust your knees and start working again, he advises. Edited excerpts:<strong>Do you think over the years the culture of acquiring and retaining talent has changed from what it was when you incepted Infosys?&amp;nbsp;</strong>First of all, we must remember that university education is all about learning to learn. Therefore, we decided not to expect any knowledge of computer science from the young engineering graduates that we recruited. Their competence and willingness to learn new things was sufficient for us. That is the reason we recruited civil engineers, mechanical engineers, physicists, mathematicians to become analysts and programmers. That is also the reason why we created the world&amp;rsquo;s largest corporate training facility in Mysore where, on a given day, we could train about 15 thousand engineers. Secondly, we must remember that we operate in an industry where the only constant is change.<strong>Being an entrepreneur is relatively easy today than it was in your time. Do you agree?&amp;nbsp;</strong>When I founded Softronics in 1976 I focused on the domestic market. I soon realized that there was hardly any domestic market for IT in India at that time. I closed Softronics, took up a job to learn about export market, and eventually I started Infosys. When I founded Infosys in 1981, we had certain types of challenges. Getting a license to import a computer was a big challenge; friction to business was huge; there was no current account convertibility; and getting a telephone connection required 7 years. Obtaining hard currency from RBI to travel abroad was very a tortuous process. Opening offices was difficult since there was no current account convertibility. Today, the challenges are different. These challenges are related to the market. Today&amp;rsquo;s challenges are about the quality of innovation that you can demonstrate in your products or services. Attracting the right quality of talent in today&amp;rsquo;s highly competitive talent market is a big challenge. So, it is difficult to say that our challenges are any tougher than the challenges faced by today&amp;rsquo;s entrepreneurs or vice-versa.When you shut down your first entrepreneurial venture Softronics, did you feel discouraged? No, there was no sadness because I realized that there was no market for software in India of the middle seventies, and that my idea was going to fail. Therefore, I decided to move on.<strong>What are your opinions on the latest economic reforms such as the move of demonetization&amp;nbsp;and introduction of goods and services tax?</strong>GST is a good move. But, the biggest economic reform that happened in the history of post-independent India is clearly the economic reforms of 1991 because they removed lots of friction to business. The successive governments after 1991 have been bringing about incremental improvements to reduce friction to business. However, even today, there are several areas that need reforms. For example, in the area of education, we have not reduced friction to business. Somehow, we have not learnt that economic reforms enhanced the velocity of business and that bringing reforms in the education sector will yield even richer dividends. Second, we have not yet introduced reforms to improve our agricultural productivity. Third, we have not yet attempted labour reforms that are required in factories and small businesses. When you have such tough regulations regarding retrenching labour, entrepreneurs are very hesitant to recruit labour in large numbers. A flexible hire-and-let-go policy with a good safety net is necessary if you want to create a large number of jobs. If we bring in all these reforms, the country will start accelerating its GDP growth rates.<strong>Will GST be of any help to the IT market since the recruitment has come to a standstill?</strong>&amp;nbsp;The IT market is mainly export-oriented where GST has no role. So, it is unlikely to help improve the IT export market.<strong>You have often mentioned the term , &amp;lsquo;Compassionate Capitalism&amp;rsquo;. What it is all about?&amp;nbsp;</strong>&amp;nbsp;Since 1974 I have been convinced that the only way a society can solve the problem of poverty is through creation of jobs. That is possible only through entrepreneurship. The free enterprise system is the best environment for unhindered entrepreneurship. Capitalism is the best system to encourage free enterprise. However, in a country like India where majority of our people live in utter poverty, it is necessary that the leaders of capitalism shun vulgar display of wealth, think about the lowest level employees in instituting compensation and benefit policies, and ensure that there is fairness in allocation of benefits of a corporation amongst various levels of employees. In other words, &amp;ldquo;compassionate capitalism&amp;rdquo; is capitalism in the mind and socialism in the heart.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 18 19:27:57 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/How-to-build-a-great-company-tells-Narayana-Murthy/18-09-2017-126435</link><title>How to build a great company, tells Narayana Murthy</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>Father of the IT industry, Co-founder of country's second largest IT sector behemoth Infosys,NR Narayana Murthy shares his style of leadership and thoughts over idea of compassionate capitalism. </description><author>Himani Chandna</author><body>Sitting in a quiet room of his Bengaluru-based office, Nagavara Ramarao Narayana Murthy&amp;rsquo;s demeanor exuded composure and humility. Father of the IT industry, co-founder of Infosys, country&amp;rsquo;s second largest IT behemoth, Murthy started the company with six other engineers in Pune in 1981 with an initial capital of Rs 10,000. It was he who introduced the global delivery model, built India&amp;rsquo;s first software campus, made Infosys the first Indian company to get listed on Nasdaq, got certification to CMM level 5 and issued one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest stock option plans.&amp;nbsp;His company was applauded for everything -- from its business model, delivery excellence, leadership to corporate governance ethics. Though Murthy retired from then $8.3-billion IT bellwether in August 2011 on turning 65 in compliance with the policy he laid down for co-founders at executive posts, the company&amp;rsquo;s board prevailed upon him to return June 1, 2013 for five years. Murthy finally bid adieu to the iconic company in 2014.&amp;nbsp;With BW People, Murthy shares his vision on &amp;lsquo;how to build a great company.<strong>Employee centric approach:</strong> Infosys was the first Indian company to offer stock options to employees in 1993, the year it went public. A total of 16,237 employees benefited until ESOPs were halted in July 2003. &amp;ldquo;Also, it was the first company in India, one of the very few in the world to have used a model called Lev and Schwartz for valuing the human resources in a company,&amp;rdquo; Murthy said. Lev and Schwartz model proposes an economic valuation of employees based on the present value of future earnings, adjusted for the probability of employees&amp;rsquo; death or separation or retirement. &amp;ldquo;We, at Infosys, believe that the most critical resources of any corporation is the quality of human mind because a human mind can innovate, invent, lead and bring about huge transformations. Therefore, the objective of any corporation will have to be to acquire as many smart and value-based professionals as possible and to create an environment of fairness, justice, meritocracy, excellence and openness so that these professionals can contribute effectively in the company,&amp;rdquo; he said. From its earliest start-up days, Murthy created a team at Infosys.&amp;nbsp;His team included stalwarts: Nandan Nilekani, the strategist and rainmaker; Kris Gopalakrishnan, the technologist; SD Shibulal, the delivery specialist; Mohandas Pai, the financial magician. Murthy held the team together while setting up processes and rules for predictability, quality, scale and growth.<strong>Create a different business proposition and never overlook your mistakes:</strong> &amp;ldquo;When I founded Softronics in 1976 I focused on the domestic market. I soon realized that there was hardly any domestic market for IT in India at that time. I closed Softronics, took up a job to learn about export market, and eventually I started Infosys.<strong>Creation of a value syste</strong><strong>m must for every entrepreneur:</strong>&amp;nbsp; Murthy says that he is a great admirer of Mahatma Gandhi who introduced the concept of leadership by example. &amp;ldquo;Gandhi also introduced the importance of walking the talk. Therefore I believe that the best form of leadership is through setting personal example. So my style of leadership is through setting an example,&amp;rdquo; Murthy said while looking out through the glass in his cabin. His posture remained serene.&amp;nbsp;In 1999, it became the first Indian company to list on the Nasdaq. It was also the first in India to report quarterly financials, issue guidance against insider trading, come up with the concept of a lead independent director, and have directors assessed by peers. &amp;nbsp;Murthy sounds very particular and confident when he shares his vision on compassionate capitalism. &amp;ldquo;In a country like India where majority of our people live in sheer poverty, it is the responsibility of capitalists to think about the lowest level of employees in instituting policies and ensuring that there is a fairness in allocation of benefits amongst various rungs of employees.<strong>Basic ingredients of a successful organisation:</strong> Honesty, hard work, integrity, transparency, fairness, accountability, austerity, leadership by example and austerity, these are all universal features which improves the probability of success. However, if someone wants to build a great company the other requirements include the understanding of conducting an inexpensive test marketing exercise. Also, every entrepreneur must know the principles of finance and sales to be successful.By following these principles you are only improving the probability of your success because every entrepreneur requires four attributes, counts Murthy. &amp;ldquo;First is competence, second is character or good values, third is commitment and fourth is chance. Nobody in the world can guarantee an entrepreneur, they can only see that if you follow these, then the probability of getting successful will increase.&amp;rdquo;Recently, Murthy said his biggest regret was quitting as chairman of Infosys in 2014, even as he has been involved in an acrimonious battle with the company&amp;rsquo;s board and management. &amp;ldquo;A lot of my founder colleagues told me not to leave Infosys in 2014, to stay a few years. Generally, I find that I am avery emotional person. A lot of my decisions are based on idealism and probably, I should have listened to them,&amp;rdquo; he told a news channel. The public spat has also brought in institutional shareholders who have said the interference from the founders was hurting the company. However, he refused talking about Infosys with BW People where he has slammed Infosys&amp;rsquo; board for poor governance and for handing out heavy pay increases to the management. During his time, he strictly followed his principle of compassionate capitalism.&amp;nbsp;</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 18 19:11:08 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/10-ways-Artificial-Intelligence-will-impact-education-sector/18-09-2017-126428</link><title>10 ways Artificial Intelligence will impact education sector</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>The clear near future benefits for AI is to assist and help teachers by taking over time consuming, grading, maintaining records and some other low value tasks. </description><author> Avinash Bharwani</author><body>With the advancement in technology, there have been ample of Next big things to watch out for in the coming years. For decades scientists and researchers have been predicting the astounding revolutions that will arise with the growth of Artificial Intelligence (AI). From the intelligent sensors that make a car drive autonomously to the mobile assistants, we are already surrounded by artificial intelligence in some way or the other at all times. Now is the time for a sector like education to initiate talks about the boon and challenges created by AI equipped teaching systems that can transform the way classrooms function.The clear near future benefits for AI is to assist and help teachers by taking over time consuming, grading, maintaining records and some other low value tasks. In addition to that, there are already newer systems that will be launched sometime soon which will raise questions on the way entire education system functions.Below are few advantages and challenges that could impact artificial intelligence:1. <strong>Time Saving for Professors/ Teach</strong><strong>er:</strong> Artificial intelligence systems can take control of many factors in classroom. It can take over control of accounting process and automated grading of student. This will free up additional time for lecturer to dedicate for classroom.2. <strong>Students could get added support from AI tutors: </strong>While there are obviously services machine can&amp;rsquo;t offer that human tutors can. In coming years the education sector will witness massive changes. Several training programs based on AI already exists and can enhance students through basic mathematics, writing, and other topic.3. <strong>Customizing AI would enhance students&amp;rsquo; health:</strong> If Artificial Intelligence permits mass customization, then it can improve student&amp;rsquo;s schedules which can be better matched to their sleep needs. This would also end the concerns of students and their parents that their children&amp;rsquo;s do not get adequate sleep.4.<strong> AI-driven functionality can give students and educators useful feedback: </strong>AI can not only help teachers and students to craft courses under syllabus that are modified to their requirements, but it also gives feedback to both students and lecturers about the success of the course as a whole. Some schools, especially those with online courses, are using such systems to scrutinize student growth and are spreading awareness amongst professors when there might be a problem with student performance. This systems permits students to get the education support system and for professors to find areas where they can improve their instruction skills for students who struggle with the topic.5. <strong>A teacher&amp;rsquo;s intuition might conflict with sensor data:</strong> AI powered voice and facial recognition can provide learning systems with data based on emotions to which they can further customize machine teaching systems.6. <strong>AI could make schoolhouses obsolete in near future: </strong>AI education systems allow for personalized curriculums that would diminish the want for classrooms and lecturers. Traditionally, schools might evolve into smaller, distributed structures and specialized learning centers.7. <strong>New reorganization to Tutoring:</strong> Studies explains that a key factor in successful training is providing instant feedback to the student after the lecture session. AI-powered apps help in effectively providing targeted, personalized feedback to the student.8.<strong> Parent-controlled education will be new and complicated:</strong> The society across the country is not familiar in a way that makes it convenient for parents to play the hands-on role that AI education may require. Similarly, this leads to critical new decisions for parents, students and employers.9.<strong> Educational application can be custom-made to student needs: </strong>From pre-school to high school, one of the essential ways artificial intelligence will impact learning is through the various software&amp;rsquo;s of greater intensity of individualized learning. Some of this is already happening through rising numbers of adaptive education programs, gaming, and software. These systems retort to the needs of the student and teachers, putting greater emphasis on certain topics. Enabling repeated lessons that students haven&amp;rsquo;t mastered, and generally helping students to work at their own pace, space and liberty.10. <strong>It can point out places where courses need to improve:</strong> The intelligence system propose a way to point out gaps and help solve various problems. As tutors sometimes are not alert of gaps in their lectures and educational courses that may put students in confused state about certain topics.AI has the potential to modify the quality, quantity, delivery, and nature of education. It also promises to change forever the role of parents, students, teachers, and educational systems. Using Artificial Intelligence systems, software and support, students can learn from across the world at any time. These kinds of applications are taking the place of certain types of classroom instruction and may replace teachers in some cases.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 18 18:16:36 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/How-companies-are-adapting-to-millennial-mindsets/18-09-2017-126396</link><title>How companies are adapting to millennial mindsets</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>With a majority of its 1.3 billion people below the age of 30, India&#8217;s key demographic is in the throes of fast economic growth. How is this young, confident and digitally-inclined workforce changing the rules of the game in the corporate world? Bernard Martyris,Chief of Human Resources, VFS Global explains how Gen Y is poised to evolve workplace for the better.</description><author>Bernard Martyris</author><body>As the world moves towards greater digitalisation, use of artificial intelligence, and big data analysis for a variety of purposes, the contours of workplaces too are undergoing dramatic shifts as a result. The fusion of physical and digital worlds is prompting a diverse range of experts to explore how the future will shape up.The millennials (the generation of people born in the 1980s and 90s, and who have reached young adulthood in the 21st century) recognise the benefits of automation in terms of productivity, possibly faster than their parents. Generally, they tend to be more inclined towards machine learning and digital platforms to facilitate business insights and decision-making in both professional and personal spheres.Gen Y has grown up with broadband, smartphones, laptops and social media being the norm and expects instant access to information. This is the first generation to enter the workplace with a better grasp of today&amp;rsquo;s key business tools than more senior workers.As they inundate the workforce and work neck-and-neck with a different generation of colleagues, corporate leaders too are seeking to understand what makes these talented and dynamic workers tick, so that they can attract, engage and retain them to re-shape the dynamism of the workplace in coming years.By 2025, over 75 per cent of the workforce will be composed of millennials who are confident, always connected online and have much more information in their hands than any other generation in human history. This enables them to be more adept consumers as well, shopping for what best meets their needs relative to the lifestyles they want.Rising aspirationsMillennials aspire for freedom and flexibility, reflected by their high value placed on a work-life balance. They work to live &amp;ndash; not live to work. They prefer to communicate via text and social media. They highly value being included in decision-making. They care about the bigger picture and want to make an impact &amp;ndash; not just at work but in their communities as well.Millennials are turned off by rigid corporate structures. They expect constant feedback, rapid progression, a varied and interesting career. Their ambition and desire to keep learning and move quickly upward through an organisation requires a focused response from employers. If the expectations of millennials are not being met, they move on.For companies, managing these expectations is a challenging prospect. On the business side, most companies need to do a better job of understanding millennials and having millennials understand them. Many organisations are changing their work environment to suit the younger generation, adopting an inclusive approach and ensuring that all different generations work together with equal opportunity and representation &amp;ndash; even in leadership roles.Looking ahead to 2020, there could be five generations in the workforce: baby boomers (born between 1946 and 1964), Gen Xers (born from 1965 to 1980) and digital natives who go beyond millennials to include generation Z (the centennials born after 2000). As jobs are made up of many tasks, the nature of existing jobs will change and new careers will be created.Companies are therefore re-aligning their strategy to connect with this new workforce through new-age recruiting tools like social media platforms, and once hired, are investing in their skills development and training to bring them up to speed with, and channel their strengths to add value to, traditional workplace processes. Synergistically, an overwhelming number of companies are also re-training people to use new technologies, or redesign jobs to better take advantage of the digitally-inclined skills of this workforce.To retain their competitive advantage, companies will need to keep reinventing the fundamentals of HR. Once this new pool of talent is part of the workforce, retaining it will require constant effort from the HR team.Millennials and Gen Z professionals follow their hearts and pursue careers while exploring their passions. Gen Z is more entrepreneurial and self-focused. These professionals see no reason why they can&amp;rsquo;t work in one department for a few days a week and in a different section on other days.&amp;lsquo;Reverse mentoring&amp;rsquo; a part of new retention programmesAs millennials need an engaging workplace, many organisations are doing away with formal office attire to semi-formal or smart work formals. HR professionals are coming up with new retention programmes like flexible work hours, remote working and collaborative work spaces.Some are even organising reverse mentoring programmes in order to pair older and/ or senior executives with the younger employees to enable cross-flow of ideas and expertise.While skilled people are good at certain roles, companies are looking at people who are curious to learn and can seamlessly move from one role to the other. Apprenticeships, online courses and certifications are being encouraged to stay relevant in the rapidly-changing industry scenario.Organisations need to harness thought diversity as an important aspect of workforce diversity. The focus will be on harnessing full potential of people &amp;ndash; a mix of full-time employees, freelancers, young and old, and all genders &amp;ndash; by acknowledging and encouraging each person&amp;rsquo;s unique perspective and ways of thinking.Traditional performance ratings, year-end rankings and reviews may eventually be phased out in some setups. HR will employ analytics to understand the needs of people in a customised, individual-specific manner and provide solutions through mobile technology and newer platforms to reduce effort spent in redundant processes.As millennials&amp;rsquo; sense of self-determination and exploration continues to grow, it becomes challenging for companies to find them &amp;ndash; and retain them. Hence, organisations will need to keep pushing the boundaries of employee engagement and find answers in new-age tools and ideas, to keep this new crop of employees engaged, motivated, and committed to adding value to common organisational goals.</body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 18 16:12:00 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Salary-Hike-May-Witness-Growth-In-2018/18-09-2017-126385</link><title>Salary Hike May Witness Growth In 2018</title><categories><category>Employer</category></categories><description>The upcoming appraisal season will see employees getting a projected average increment of 9.6 percent, up from 9.4 percent this year</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Salary hike might go past its worst eight-year low in 2018, and as per HR consultancy firm Aon Hewitt, we may see brighter days ahead.The upcoming appraisal season will see employees getting a projected average increment of 9.6 percent, up from 9.4 percent this year, according to initial findings of HR consultancy Aon Hewitt&amp;rsquo;s India Salary Increase Survey.Professional services firms that were overloaded inundated with work during the transition to the GST rule; are expected to lead the way with the biggest pay hikes, projected at 10.7 percent. Life sciences and vehicle manufacturing may well see good hikes of 10.6 percent and 10.4 percent respectively.Meanwhile, the much happening high-technology sector going through a dull phase is expecting an average hike of 9.9 percent in 2018 compared to an average of 9.7 percent in 2017, against the low market expectations.Anandorup Ghosh, partner at Aon Hewitt said that it could be because IT product and IT consulting companies that fared much better, dispersed increments that made up for the low increments given by third party IT services players.Ghosh added, &amp;ldquo;IT product and consulting organisations are showing a positive trend on the back of local demand. However, cost arbitrage business continues to be under pressure with shrinking overseas demand, current exchange rates and focus on lower segment of value chain.&amp;rdquo;India has the highest inflation-adjusted salary increases in the world, even after giving hikes less than 10 percent for two consecutive years.Sectors with lowest forecast of hike in 2018 include hospitality (8.9 percent), engineering design (8.8 percent), banking/finance (8.6 percent), and logistics service (8.6 percent).The study reveals that maintaining competitiveness of pay continues to be a top reward challenge for firms, especially given that 71.9 percent companies reported salary increase budgets to be same as 2017.<br><br></body><post-date>Mon, 2017 Sep 18 15:26:50 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Nearly-40-Future-Jobs-In-India-Will-Demand-Different-Skill-Sets/17-09-2017-126327</link><title>Nearly 40% Future Jobs In India Will Demand Different Skill Sets</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>The internet and exponential technologies are creating new employment opportunities in the areas of &#8216;white-collar&#8217; working</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Almost 9 percent of the workforce in the future would be deployed in new jobs that do not exist today.According to a report titled &amp;lsquo;The future of skills and jobs in India&amp;rsquo; by FICCI and NASSCOM with Ernst and Young, by 2022 nearly 37 percent of Indian workforce would be in jobs demanding radically different skill sets.The report highlights the impact that various primary forces such as globalization, demographics, and Industry technologies, are expected to have on the key sectors of the economy.The internet and exponential technologies are creating new employment opportunities in the areas of &amp;lsquo;white-collar&amp;rsquo; working. In India, the future of jobs in 2022 would be determined by the country&amp;rsquo;s response to 12 megatrends which includes, under globalization - the level of exports, rapid adoption of exponential technologies, increasing/shrinking overseas job market for Indian workforce and level of FDI flows.&amp;nbsp;Almost 60-65 percent workforce in the organized IT/BPM sector would be deployed in jobs that have radically changed skill sets including Embedded System Programmer, Data Scientist, Data Architect and AI Research Scientist among a few. &amp;nbsp;Similarly, 50-55 percent in the automotive sector would be deployed in jobs that have radically changed skill sets and evolving job roles. New jobs roles are also expected in the Textile &amp;amp; Apparel, BFSI and Retail sector.Mohandas Pai, Chairman, FICCI Skill Development Committee &amp;amp; Chairman Manipal Global Education, said that there was an urgent need to collate and analyze data to understand the sectors in which jobs were being created, what were the skills that were needed by industries and employers, and how productivity could be enhanced with re-skilling of workforce.&amp;nbsp;</body><post-date>Sun, 2017 Sep 17 18:09:04 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/India-To-Have-20-crore-Unemployed-People-By-2025-Says-Pai/15-09-2017-126298</link><title>India To Have 20 crore Unemployed People By 2025, Says Pai</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>Mohan Das Pai, Chairman, FICCI Skill Development Committee said that we need to prepare for skills that will last 40 years. The change in technology in the last 15 years has been greater than the previous 50 years

</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>Automation and Artificial Intelligence is feared to take away jobs from the market. But experts in skill development believe that redefined skills can meet the challenges thrown up by the constantly evolving technology.At FICCI&amp;#39;s 10th Global Skills Summit Mohan Das Pai, Chairman, FICCI Skill Development Committee said that we need to prepare for skills that will last 40 years. The change in technology in the last 15 years has been greater than the previous 50 years.Mohan Das Pai added, &amp;ldquo;We have been creating 60-70 lakh jobs per year. With a growth rate of around 7 percent, it is impossible that jobs are not being created. In this age of disruption, we need to develop skills to meet the challenges. Unless we focus on skill development, there will be around 20 crore people without jobs by 2025.&amp;rdquo; &amp;nbsp;Skills development minister Dharmendra Pradhan, focused on creating an ecosystem where Indians can feel they can skill themselves and play the role of job creation in the country.Pradhan added, &amp;ldquo;We missed growth opportunity in the last industrial revolution. We are focusing to create an ecosystem so that India does not miss on the Industrial Revolution 4.0. India has only 10 percent skilled white-collar jobs and its biggest challenge will be to take 1-1.5 crore workforce to a level where they are skilled enough to earn their livelihood.&amp;rdquo;Attending the summit, Simon Bartley, president of WorldSkills International said,&amp;rdquo;India will develop enormously fast if it embraces development of skills for all and not just few. He focused on the fact that skills are more important than education in today&amp;rsquo;s world. It is important to implement all the skills you have. There are jobs but people need to be upgraded.&amp;rdquo; &amp;nbsp;He further focused on the fact that India is missing in the list of top 10 countries in the world skills competition and challenged India to take it up and improve.</body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Sep 15 18:25:25 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Sun-Pharma-Took-Two-Years-To-Integrate-Ranbaxy-s-Employees/15-09-2017-126257</link><title>Sun Pharma Took Two Years To Integrate Ranbaxy&#8217;s Employees</title><categories><category>Employee</category></categories><description>While Sun Pharmaceuticals started out the process of easing out excess employees from Ranbaxy, company also undertook several initiatives to relax and motivate the rest

</description><author>Himani Chandna</author><body>Touted as one of the most complex merger in terms of human resources, Sun Pharmaceuticals has finally completed the integration process of Ranbaxy&amp;rsquo;s employees. The exercise was termed intense due to the sheer size of the two firms where the sales force of the combined organisation was close to 30,000 in India and overseas, as per the industry estimates.&amp;ldquo;Mergers and acquisitions are not common in India as they are abroad. We took two years to integrate employees of Ranbaxy into Sun Pharmaceuticals. In two years we designed, planned and executed the plan to conclude the merger of people,&amp;rdquo; said Yashwant Mahadik, executive vice president &amp;amp; global CHRO, Sun Pharma.While Sun Pharmaceuticals started out the process of easing out excess employees from Ranbaxy, company also undertook several initiatives to relax and motivate the rest. &amp;ldquo;It is natural that there was a bit of uncertainty among employees. However, Ranbaxy was a top pharma company and its human resources were valuable. We drove various initiatives to undertake a smooth integration process,&amp;rdquo; Mahadik said.Company educated Ranbaxy&amp;rsquo;s employees, made them aware of what Sun is planning to do, made new policies and motivated the employees through several inter-office meetings as well.Company in 2015 also said that, &amp;quot;In order to make this (integration) happen, the company has made and will continue to make all efforts to utilise the total available talent in the most appropriate manner. If there are a few employees who could not be positioned appropriately, the organisation will make all attempts to handle the same in a fair, transparent and sensitive manner. We reiterate that our focus continues to be on creating an environment of meaningful professional opportunities for our employees to lead, succeed and grow.&amp;quot;In March 2015, the merger of Sun Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd, India&amp;rsquo;s most valuable drug maker, has completed the $3.2 billion acquisition of Ranbaxy Laboratories Ltd after almost a year of navigating the regulatory gauntlet to create the world&amp;rsquo;s fifth-biggest generic pharmaceutical company by revenue.</body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Sep 15 14:03:22 UTC</post-date></node><node><link>http://bwpeople.businessworld.in//article/Worried-About-Jobs-Automation-Will-Not-Make-You-Jobless/15-09-2017-126255</link><title>Worried About Jobs? Automation Will Not Make You Jobless</title><categories><category>Jobs</category></categories><description>It is important to know about the jobs of tomorrow, with technology evolving rapidly. While it may take away some jobs, innovation and technology can help in creating niche jobs</description><author>Rajguru Tandon</author><body>You might be worried about automation taking away your job! But if head hunters are to be believed, you might not.While a finding by HfS Research shows that technology will take away one-third low skilled jobs by 2022, top notch companies such as tech giant HCL Technologies, aviation leader IndiGo and Udacity believe that technology might end up changing your job role - you might end up doing the same job but with technological advancements.What will be the future of jobs? It is important to know about the jobs of tomorrow, with technology evolving rapidly. While it may take away some jobs, innovation and technology can help in creating niche jobs.Talking about the challenges at the SHRM India Annual Conference &amp;amp; Exposition 2017, Sukhjit Pasricha, VP HR at Indigo said, &amp;ldquo;We are also seeing the change. We have been focusing on digital learning, digital analytics and virtual workforce, and connect employees through smart phones now. Going forward, we will bring technology to serve customers and employees alike. We are collaborating with airports where people will self-serve themselves for the boarding pass and all other services.&amp;rdquo;On the same challenges, Subrat Chakravarty, HR head, HCL Technologies said, &amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence is not only affecting the IT sector, but every industry. We are not seeing it for the first time. The difference is that the clients are more educated. It has been a sudden change in demand in the industry, and skills are needed to cope up with the trends. We are still scratching only 15 percent of the digital market.&amp;rdquo;Sukhjit Pasricha further added, &amp;ldquo;The jobs will not go away, but will be transformed. There are some jobs that will be taken away, but there are a whole lot of niche jobs that will be created. Skill demands are changing, and we really need to focus on re-skilling, since the world will be more contractive and connected digitally.&amp;rdquo;Clarissa Shen, VP International and MD, Asia, Udacity said, &amp;ldquo;Automation and artificial intelligence will help in simplifying the work done by the humans. &amp;nbsp;On an average, it takes 35 days for technology to be adopted. Time for traditional learning has gone. With technology advancing rapidly, it is important for people to indulge in lifelong learning.&amp;rdquo;</body><post-date>Fri, 2017 Sep 15 13:56:33 UTC</post-date></node></nodes>